Heat. Heat.
Good evening. Evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to the ask a
show. I hope you're all doing great. I'm
going to take questions from the live
from the super chat today and uh before
we do that let me see who all is there
on the live chat. So who do we have? We
have Jayant Yadav X no holy banerjee Sri
Ram Chundraa pranamutra
birad minimalist maverick pascar bandit
pascar bandit Sri Ram chundra once again
u humanity survives an
geopolitical dub from Indor Pascar
bandit once again swatiku
beckenbower
general subatai hello um Yash Patel
Adwit Ashani Sabarish Na Rohani Harum
Raika Ham Ma'am Bascar Bandit once again
Ritik Paw Rohan BD Apura Anupama Namaste
SKR7733 Swami C0709 Aayush Singh Pranam
Sarji Apurva Anupama SKR once again Sam
the gamer good evening Avin Bascar
Bandit is here from Moscow good evening
good evening lucky Badwaj
G78807
real braimir Putin Ram Ram Sarji Himmanu
Rajurohit from Tamil Nadu, the land of
Dharma. Well, yeah. Uh GK GK87, good
morning. Good morning to you. Manhattan
Swami is here from Jaipur. Himmanu Raj
Rohit once again. Um who else?
Um okay, happy defender of the
fatherland Russian war war holiday
today. Fantastic. Fantastic. Uh same to
you. Ain is also here. Swami Hot flame
edits Himmanshu Lag onlinear mahadev
brave robot is cooking fish today. Meow.
Okay, good for you sir. Good enjoy it.
Random skull. Jes Krishna Swami. Uh who
else? Raguir Soleni. Uh Amisha Mishra
hello good evening ma'am. Mak 4 Jvu
Hitman is also here with us. Gpat 79.
Kahan is here from Delhi. Jascaran Singh
good morning sir. Good morning to you.
Toxic Krathos, fantasmic.
Um,
who else? Um, Sergeant Skylin is here
with us. Good evening, YKK 3096
and and lots and lots of other people.
Who else? Soldier Boy is here. Anime
Baratia
SP Arouch X Gamer Rule World Tasi Sajan.
Um,
who else do we have? Shreas Mitra is
also here from Moscow. Okay, we have two
people from Moscow here. That's
fantastic. Uh, Ganesh Desh Pande,
Gajapati Dave, hello and everybody else.
Okay, Manisha Kardo, namaste, good
evening ma'am. Uh, Ethim Sat, good
evening Char and everyone else. Okay,
let's get going with some questions.
There's a lot happening in the world.
Rashma Banu is also here who says, okay,
Israel and Iran, Israel says they will
use nukes against Iran. We'll see about
that. We'll see about that. Yeah. Okay.
Okay, so let's get going with some
questions. First of all, Noli Banerji
has become a new member of this channel.
Thank you very much, ma'am. Ma'am, I
think it is. Yep. And welcome to the
channel's membership. Minimalist
Maverick says Gore command visit. Okay.
The US ambassador Sergio Gore visited
the western command of the Indian uh
army.
So the Gore command visit uh Iran oil
tanker seizure by India. Perplexingly,
India seized three oil tankers belonging
to Iran apparently. Explain this
possibility hypothetical deal between
India and US to invade Iran for
pro-India government in Iran to make
China and Russia Vasal.
We currently have a pro-India government
or at least not anti-India government in
Iran. The current government in Iran,
the regime of the Ayatas,
it may not be entirely pro- India but
it's definitely not anti-India. They are
anti-Pakistan.
Okay. So ask my question is why would we
want to remove that government?
Because if the Americans do a regime
change and they bring in a pro- US
government is going to be pro Pakistan.
So why would there be a deal between
India and the US to remove this
government in Iran which is
anti-Pakistan and not anti-India? Why?
What sense does it make? Where's the
logic? Think about it. Where's the
logic? and India invading Iran. India is
not going to invade even Bhutan.
India is not going to assist the US and
assist the US in invading Iran. There's
no question about it. India doesn't do
these things.
Um and India will make China and Russia
vasal. I mean
even the Americans can't make China and
Russia vasals right now. So forget about
India doing that or India teaming up
with the US in doing that. So the
question is why did India allow this guy
Sergio Gore the US ambassador to visit
um India's the Indian army's western
command. Obviously Sergio Gore did not
go there alone. He went with a team of
people which includes military personnel
which will also include some of the
diplomats who are simply diplomats in
disguise. They're actually CIA agents.
Military ataches and diplomatic atashes
and cuisine attaches or whatever they
are typically CIA agents. So these
people accompanied Serjugore in visiting
the Indian army's western command. A
bunch of spies were allowed by India to
enter the Indian army's western command.
Why has India done this? This is
typically never done.
See in Israel
if you are a foreign diplomat you are
automatically considered to be a spy
automatically you're a spy that's it
that's how they see you so why did India
allow a bunch of spies foreign spies to
enter the western oil the western
command of the Indian army makes no
sense to me it sounds like a very vasal
move from my perspective then India
seizes three Iranian oil tankers
What sense does it make? Once again, um
I don't have answers to these questions
right now. Why has India done these
things? Why did we allow a bunch of
foreign spies to to visit our western
command? Think about it. American spies,
you can call them diplomats, but
diplomats are spies. Understand that
very clearly. Okay? This is the real
world of grown-ups we're living in, not
the world of ethandard and seventh
standard. Diplomats are spies.
So, American spies. Now, understand
this. America supports Pakistan. America
saved Pakistan during Operation Sindur.
America is using various proxies to arm
Pakistan. Whether it's Saudi Arabia,
whether it's whatever
Munir visits Donald Trump very often,
right? So, the US is a proakistan
nation. The US has a strategy and a
policy of containing India. The US is
doing regime change all all around the
subcontinent to ring fence India. The US
is behaving like a hostile power
and we are allowing a bunch of spies
into the western command which faces
Pakistan. So these spies will observe
what our military posture is against
Pakistan, a nation they support. What?
What is this?
It makes no sense whatsoever unless we
are an American vasal. I am not still
claiming we are American vasal but uh
yeah this is a very strange move
and then seizing Iranian oil tankers. So
very strange what we are doing makes no
sense from a sovereignty perspective
from a national interest perspective.
What is the Modi government doing? I
wonder.
Basar Bandit says Pyth great. Okay. Yes
of course I'm doing great. how you
doing? Uh we know the US allegedly gives
protection money to Afghanistan to
allegedly keep China and some others
out. But why not lift and ease up the
sanctions in Afghanistan? Well, if you
ease the sanctions on Afghanistan, then
you don't have leverage left in
Afghanistan.
Those sanctions are leverage.
You want Afghanistan to behave, then you
use two strategies simultaneously. The
carrot and the stick.
What is the carrot? It is this money,
this weekly stipend in in cash that the
Americans pay to the Taliban. Allegedly
anything between 30 to 50 to$100 million
a week in cash. So that is the carrot.
But there has to be a stick as well. The
stick is the sanctions and what not. And
it's not just the US that has imposed
sanctions on the Taliban, on
Afghanistan. It's a bunch of US vasals,
European countries, etc. who have also
imposed sanctions on Afghanistan.
So that's what they do. You use a dual
strategy, parallel strategies, the
carrot and the stick together to get the
nation to behave. That's how you do it.
Why ease up the sanctions? Why?
Okay. Nazcar Bandit says, "You mentioned
some weeks ago that you might consider
bringing geostrategy episodes back.
Should we expect them soon? I still
haven't decided." Uh, let's see.
Let's see.
Yeah, I'll let you guys know soon.
Basket Bandit says uh as an NRI
anti-India stance online seems uh to be
at at an all-time high today uh started
around sleepy Jews time we discussed
that having thick skin is important but
a can can a common Indian counter this
like on Instagram there is too much
negativity now a common Indian can do
what a common Indian does you know post
on social media if you feel like
beyond that what can a common person do
a common person is one individual what
you can do is you post on social media
pro India posts that's the best you can
do or you can get your friends together
and you all build up a strategy of what
you're going to do on social media you
know uh three three people can be you
know assigned the task this task of
posting let's say 10 times a day on
Twitter three people will do it on
Instagram three will do on Facebook or
whatever that's something you can do as
as individuals but beyond that what can
Indians do you know ordinary people uh
so yeah This anti-India
propaganda is definitely reaching
all-time highs. No question about that.
Online, right? All kinds of negative
posting about India uh and and so on.
And it all began during Sleepy Joe's
time. It actually began around 2022.
It began after India refused to
participate in the American sanctions
against Russia after Russia's Russia
began its special military operation in
Ukraine. That's when this entire uh
barrage
of anti-India posts began on social
media. It was not just social media
posts. It's also think tank articles uh
you know news news reports and news
articles uh in the western media on
western television and so on. It's
podcasts all that it's it's a concerted
campaign.
So that's what Indians can do as
individuals.
Uh okay, Baskar Mannet again says, "How
did Russia acquire fifth generation
engine? If the US developed their own by
spending spending billions plus research
and China allegedly stole the American
blueprints, YouTube denied my super chat
about this question earlier." Okay.
Really? Uh see,
China hasn't stolen any American
blueprints of uh jet engines.
China stole American designs of fifth
generation fighter planes uh such as the
F-35 for for example. So that's what's
what China stole. U I'm not sure if they
stole jet engine blueprints. Even if you
have blueprints of a jet engine, you
need to fabricate it. And fabrication is
the is the big deal, right? You have to
be able to fabricate those materials
that can withstand those incredibly high
temperatures. So having a blueprint
isn't enough. It's it's it's nothing
really worthless. What China did is
China has been reverse engineing the
Russian Saturn engines. Now the first So
that's about China. Now about your
question about Russia. How did Russia
acquire a fifth generation fighter, a
jet engine?
Russia
had a fourth generation engine.
Then before that, Russia had a third
generation engine. Before that, Russia
had a second generation engine. Before
that, Russia had a first generation
engine. Russia has been designing and
developing its own engines. It has never
acquired technology from somewhere else.
Russia's fifth generation Saturn engine
Saturn 41 or whatever it is. It's a
completely Russian design. They haven't
acquired this technology from somebody
else. They have developed over decades
their their jet engine technology. So
the Sukoy 30, Sukoy 27 etc. they have
the Saturn 31N or whatever engine,
right? That's a fourth generation jet
engine. And now the Sukoy 57, the new
one has the Saturn 41N or whatever it is
uh jet engine. Let's let's quickly take
a look at the the uh generations of
Saturn engines. Uh Saturn
One second. Saturn 41N jet engine.
Uh okay. I to press enter. Okay. Uh
yeah, it's AL41. It's not N. It's 40.
AL41 F1. It's an Russian high
performance after burning turboan engine
developed by NPO Saturn for fifth
generation stealth fighters. It's the
primary power plant for the Sukoya 57 uh
stealth fighter. So yeah, so the
Russians haven't acquired this
technology. They have developed it.
Okay. And YouTube denied a super chat
earlier about this question. Very
interesting indeed.
Basar says, "What scientific
breakthroughs can we expect in the next
50 to 100 years in space exploration? Is
humanity reaching closer to mining
asteroids given we will exhaust or
destroy earth reserves of rare earth
elements and other stuff?" See, when it
comes to space exploration, the
breakthroughs aren't scientific
breakthroughs. These are engineering
breakthroughs. Okay? The breakthroughs
are engineering breakthroughs, not
scientific breakthroughs. Um so what can
we expect? I suppose the first
breakthrough which is kind of being
being broken through right now is
extremely heavy lift uh rockets like the
uh
Starship that that that SpaceX is
developing. So SpaceX uh it has this uh
very heavy lift rocket called Starship.
The most powerful reco rocket ever built
and uh it's going to be tested again
next month. It's going to be launched
again next month. So that's the first
breakthrough that's kind of right right
here right now. What else can we have?
Uh we're going to have human a human
presence on on the moon. So Elon Musk
has now pivoted from away from Mars and
towards the moon because it's way easier
to get to the moon. And so the the
mission is no longer Mars. It's mission
moon now. And that's something that
could happen in the next 2 three years.
So we're going to have eventually in the
next 5 10 years the first human bases
permanent bases on the moon. By the
2030s we're going to have probably
humans on Mars. So that's another uh
engineering breakthrough, technological
breakthrough and historical breakthrough
essentially. Uh so you're going to have
the first human human missions to Mars
and eventually there's going to be uh uh
permanent human settlements on Mars as
well. Maybe by the 2040s, maybe by 2050
around that time. So that's about Mars.
When it comes to U so that's the kind of
thing you will going to you're going to
have you're going to have more uh you're
going to have more space stations in
orbit around the earth. You also will
eventually possibly have space stations
in orbit around Mars and um the moon as
well possibly but probably just Mars
bases and moon bases starting with the
moon. Uh about asteroid mining
is not going to happen in the next 50 or
100 years. Asteroid mining may happen in
the next maybe 200 years. Maybe I'm
wrong. Maybe I'm wrong. Maybe AI and
robotics will give us the technology. We
need to start mining asteroids in this
century itself perhaps. Right? Possible,
but I would say still improbable because
asteroids are really really far away.
They are in the asteroid belt. So there
are multiple asteroid belts but the
closest one is the asteroid belt that's
in orbit between u the orbits of Mars
and and and Jupiter.
So that's where you have this big big
big field of debris which is asteroids
and it looks when we when we discuss
this it sounds like the the asteroids
are all all grouped together very
closely packed together but actually
they are millions of kilometers apart.
Any two given asteroids are millions of
kilometers apart. The earth moon
distances of what's the earth moon
distance? Let's find out. Okay let's see
what's the earth moon distance.
See, it's not even a million kilometers.
It's like 0.4 million kilometers. And
asteroids are typically millions of
kilometers apart from each other. And
they are really really far away. So
locating asteroids, detecting what you
know minerals and and and other elements
they contain, then reaching the
asteroid, then actually starting a
drilling and mining operation, then
bringing the stuff back to Earth. It's
going to be really difficult. Of course,
it doesn't break the laws of physics.
definitely 100% possible, but it's it's
going to be a real breakthrough whenever
it happens. So,
if you let's say you want to mine gold
or silver or rare earth elements, how do
you know which asteroid contains that?
You're going to have to send probes,
autonomous probes to various asteroids
which will then reach the asteroid, land
on the asteroid, then start drilling
there from various angles to figure out
what the asteroid contains. So that's
going to be a long process. It's not
going to happen
soon, right? So maybe it's something
that will happen in the next 100 200
years. But AI and robotics, if we have
major breakthroughs in these fields,
maybe it may happen sooner, but
definitely not in the next 50 years. So
that's how I see things going. Okay.
Uh Basker Bandit says, "Congrats on the
333rd episode." Thank you very much,
sir. Grateful to be part of this
journey. more power and support to you
for raising for helping us raise our
standards. Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you very much to you and everybody
else. I'm very very indeed very
grateful. Thank you.
Aniket says, "Experts say that the real
population of China is 800 million based
on salt consumption plus nighttime
light. Satellite imagery shows inflated
GDP person and population 10% of China's
edible oil comes from gutter oil 2010
research while some people have raised
these concerns if you look at the
nighttime luminosity
of the nation of China in satellite
imagery in satellite images you will
find that India is way more luminous
significantly visibly more luminous than
China.
So, China is not that that bright in in
nighttime satellite images.
That kind of raises question mark,
right? So, that's one, you know, that's
one example of of uh you know, facts not
matching claims. The claim is that
China's population is 1.4 billion. Uh
then when it when it comes to other
things like salt consumption, etc., once
again, it looks like China's population
is lower than what is being claimed. um
GDP also there's been this longstanding
uh and persistent
uh you know claim made by various people
over time experts over time that China's
GDP that the Chinese government has been
inflating its GDP its actual GDP growth
is much lower than what they claim and
it's the China's China as a nation its
overall GDP is lower than what China the
Chinese government claims um I suppose
experts will know about this obviously I
haven't done you know statistical
detailed research on this so I can't say
but yeah these suspicions
aren't random suspicions very very
highly placed and very uh wellinformed
people have been raising these
suspicions and these doubts this you
know uh
so yeah it's it's possible that China
actually is is hiding the truth from the
rest of the world uh about China's
edible oil comes from gutter oil okay I
haven't seen Gutter oil. I didn't even
know what gutter oil was was until I saw
some videos from China in which you open
a sewer and you apparently extract oil
out of sewers
and some restaurants use that you know
to I mean for cooking. So um 10% if it's
true that would be shocking but uh the
point is every nation has issues every
nation has problems. Yeah. uh since we
are Indians, we know exactly what kind
of problems we have. And I assure you
that India's problems are much bigger
than those of China's. So let's let's
also remember that let's not gloat about
China's problems. If if China has
problems, of course they have. Uh the
thing is we should focus on our own
country. We know what problems we have.
we know uh
what what direction we have to go in and
we need to focus on that more than uh
China. Of course, we should know what's
going on in China. No question about
that. So, I'm not saying that these uh
points you've raised are not valid. They
are very much valid indeed.
Okay. Swastik says if Chanaka was alive
today, his vision for the country, what
fields would he want Barat to dominate?
Which leader would he approve to rule
Barat from with absolute iron fist? And
what elements get crushed?
Okay. What would Chanaka's vision for
Barat be if he were alive today? He
would want Barat to excel in all fields,
especially science and technology,
especially technology. And for a nation
to excel in technology, you have to
excel in science. And for that, you need
a world-class education system. Right?
So Chanaki would want India to excel in
technology because without technological
excellence you are not any kind of
power. You are you are a useless power.
You are not even a power if you depend
on other nations for technology. So what
kind of technologies? Military
technology uh civilian technology
artificial intelligence uh
semiconductors electronics
aviation jet engines submarines
everything all of that. So he would want
Barat to be world class in all of these
fields for sure. Right? Uh he would also
want Bhat to be a net exporter of
culture rather than being a net importer
of culture like we are today.
Yeah. He would want Bat dominate to be a
dominant cultural power, a net exporter
of culture. Which leader would he
approve to Rud Bat? Someone who is not
secular.
He would not want somebody who secular.
So I'll not start giving you names of
what leaders he would approve because I
am not Chanaka.
But Chanaka would not want secular
leaders.
He would definitely not want that. He
would want dharmic leaders. What
elements get crushed? Well any
anti-inational or anti-vilivilizational
elements will get crushed thoroughly by
him with an iron fist fist or by whoever
uh he mentors and and uh you know
appoints as the emperor. Obviously if if
if
he were to be alive today he would not
approve of this so-called democratic
system that we have and this so-called
constitution that we have he would not
approve of that. He would want there to
be an emperor to rule Bat. That's what
Chanaka would want. You think Chanaka
would be pleased with this so-called
democracy that we have today?
He would be disgusted with it.
Okay?
This democracy with the upper house of
parliament, lower house of parliament
and a prime minister and a constitution
that is not even ratified by the people
of India. Do you think he'll approve of
it? He'll be disgusted by it. So
understand Chanaki had standards. We are
we no longer are at those standards. He
would be disgusted with us today. I mean
is this Bharat vers today in the 21st
century? He would be disgusted.
That's the truth.
Beckinbau says um
big fan of your channel. Thank you sir.
Have you heard about the Kodu Galore
massacre of Jews by Zamarind kings of
Kerala?
heard the story from my grand from my
grandpa.
Kudu galore massacre of Jews.
There's been no massacre of Jews in
India ever
by the Samudri kings of Kerala. The
Zamorins this word Zamorin is a
Portuguese word. The Portuguese
obviously could not speak Indian
languages. So they turned Samudri into
Zamorin.
The kings were called samudri kings.
They used to be seafaring kings. Samudra
right obviously
so the kings of Kerala like the king of
Kalikat hol was called the samudri
in the Portuguese called them zamarans
so essentially the kings of Kerala so
are you saying that there's been a
massacre of Jews by the Hindu kings of
Kerala I have never heard of this
never ever heard of this I don't think
it can be true I don't think there's
ever be any kind of massacre of Jews in
India I mean what let's let's see
Uh kodalore. What is kodalore? Kodalore.
Kodungalur.
Okay.
Massacre of Jews by Zamuran kings of
Kerala.
Uh
Jewish. Um okay. This is some nonsense
that has been propagated by Reddit
apparently.
Muslim forces etc. Safe heaven, Jewish
chronicle, massacre of Jews. Okay, I
don't know. This is some new fangled new
history. It looks like
I don't know who has invented this new
story. I've never heard of this. I've
never I've never heard of this.
Yeah, this is new. Okay, now we are
inventing stories of Indians massacing
Jews. That's interesting. I don't know.
I've never heard of it. This is not real
history the way I mean for from whatever
I know.
Okay.
Sabarish says after following your
insights for a long time now, Raj
Shamani's podcast with Mako felt more
like diplomatic nasties than a realistic
talk where France is already America's
vasal and we are on the verge of
becoming a vasal. So I don't watch
podcasts first of all. I don't have the
time for that. I haven't watched u this
uh podcast with Mu Mak. Uh so I'm I'm
not aware of what uh was discussed, what
was not discussed.
Um see if Mu Mako agrees to doing a
podcast in India, we will obviously do
it on the recommendation of the
government of India. So it looks like
the government of India is recommending
Mr. Raj Shamani for whatever reason.
Okay, good. So in that case, the
podcaster, the person who is the host
will definitely not ask any tough
questions or do any cross-examining of
or whatever of the host or of the guest,
right? When you're hosting uh the the
president of France, you don't do that.
So then obviously it'll be a podcast
full of nisties, right? So okay. So I'm
not sure what purpose it really serves
but u maybe it's something the
government of India wanted to do as a
favor to Mr. Mak that you appear on an
Indian podcast and we recommend this
particular gentleman who is a fantastic
podcaster. Maybe that's the case. Um
France is obviously we know yeah from
the analysis we have done so many times
on this channel France is an American.
It's a member of the EU. It's a member
of NATO. that makes you the vasal and we
India are on the verge of becoming an
American vasal. Should I agree or
disagree with this? I will say
I will say I will repeat what I've said
in the past the past few weeks that
there is a high probability that India
becomes an American vasal in the next 5
years. Are we there yet?
I'll I'll not say that we are there yet
but we may be perhaps showing signs of
being on our way there. Yeah,
Ritip says, "Are we still at the in the
infancy of the AI revolution?" Actually,
we are. We are. We are still in the
infancy of the AI revolution. There's a
lot that AI can't do. One example of
what AI can't do is this.
See if you give AI all the physics data,
physics knowledge, physics information
from let's say 1908,
1908, whatever was known to the world,
whatever know was known to physicists
in 1908. If we give all that information
to AI, can AI come up with the general
theory of relativity? Einstein's general
relativity which Einstein worked on
between 1908 to 1915. Can AI come up
with that on its own and right now AI
can't do that. So AI is still in its
infancy. AI is still taking baby steps.
AI still gets lost. It still gets
confused. If the context window is too
large I mean if there's too much context
it gets bogged down. There's many
problems with AI right now. But AI is
evolving very rapidly. So we are still
kind of at the infancy of the AI
revolution. AI is still right now mostly
chat bots and now we have things like
co-work and code and command line
interfaces and whatnot but it's still
you could say in its infancy. AI hasn't
been given real agency yet.
What's agency? Uh the ability to do
things in the real world. Right now it's
just building software for people. Um
you analyzing documents for people,
building marketing plans for people. U
generating reports for people. uh
writing code like I said deploying app
no not deploying but building apps and
so on and so forth that's what AI is
doing it's all software related stuff um
some AI can edit videos and audio stuff
and all that but once again it's
software related stuff so AI isn't yet
able to do things in the real world that
agency hasn't been given to AI so I
think it'll take another 2 three years
maybe 5 years by 2030 we're going to
have a whole different AI landscape so
we are still essentially In the in the
infancy of the AI revolution,
Rohan Biri says negativity unites people
more than positivity is it due to
survival survival instinct of the
reptilian brain?
I think that's a psychological trait I
think that humanity kind of seems to
have. Negativity unites people more than
positivity. See, negativity is obviously
uh some kind of threat, right? some kind
of threat. Negativity
implies some kind of threat of some
kind.
And when there's a threat, your survival
in instincts are triggered. Question, no
question about that. And when you have a
shared threat, you know, that's when
your shared survival in instincts come
together
and that's how people band together. So
when everything is fantastic, when
everything is going well,
everybody goes in their own lane and
does whatever they do, everybody can be
happy in their own way. But when you
suffer, you suffer together in the same
way, I suppose. So I think uh maybe it's
a psychological thing, maybe it's about
a shared common threat that you that you
face when there is negativity. And
that's why I don't know if is if it's
the reptilian brain or some other part
of the brain, but definitely it's about
a shared thread.
So yeah,
when there's a threat, you are more
likely to take action or at least uh
have conversations about what to do
about the thing. So maybe that's why
negativity unites people more than
positivity.
Godliness says mha ministry of home
affairs came up today with prahar
anti-terror force. It's secular mentions
terrorism has no faith ideology,
religion or civilizational context.
Secularism is good but this government
is now becoming a joke. Okay. So I
haven't seen this uh I'm not aware of
this prahar anti-terror force. Let's
let's see let's uh Google this.
Okay. So prahar anti-terror force.
Um
now okay prahar it's a two it's two a's
India's new policy prahar to bring down
the hammer on terrorism
and is there a circular okay is this the
circular
8 hours ago will it open I don't know
why the ministry of home affairs
websites don't open very easily it's not
opening it's loading loading loading
and it won't open for whatever reason
okay so the the thing is I haven't seen
the circular. Um, now officially the
government of India is a secular
government. Officially India is a
secular nation. Our uh constitution def
defines India as a what? Secular
socialist republic
and so on.
Right? So the prime minister of India,
the government of India, they they
follow the constitution. They worship
the constitution.
It is what it is.
Right?
It's the nature of India today. India is
a secular nation and we have to
be secular. So if that displeases you,
maybe you should we should those who are
displeased with this, they should
perhaps do something about this. Is the
government of India becoming a joke?
Well, uh I shall not comment about that.
Secularism is good.
My question, my question is why do we
need to be secular? Why can't we be
dharmic?
I think being dharmic is superior to
being secular.
Right? So it is what it is. This is the
nature of India today. Standards are
different compared to the days of Vishnu
Gupta Chanaka. Very different standards.
Very low much lower standards.
Pratam
Pratam Medar says what's happening in
Guadalajara Mexico before FIFA World
Cup. Is the next FIFA World Cup going to
be in Mexico? I'm not sure. Let's see
where is the next FIFA World Cup going
to be held.
Um, okay. Canada, Mexico, and the USA?
The entirety of North America. Well, how
nice. Okay. Uh, and when? Let's see.
When?
When? When when? So,
which year? Is it 2026? Really? Is it
this year? I wasn't aware. I remember
doing um I remember doing a live stream
during the final match of the 20 of the
last World Cup
uh where Messi I mean Argentina won
right so is has it been is it has it
been four years now I can't believe how
fast time time flies okay so the 2026
FIFA World Cup will be held in those
countries
from June 11 to July 19 2026 well we
have a world cup world up coming up. I
was not aware of this. So what's
happening in Guadalajara? Some kind of
terrorist attack, cartel attack.
Apparently the government of Mexico took
down took down the leader of one of the
cartels and the cartel has responded in
full force and they are terrorizing a
city and they have taken over parts of a
city and there's like essentially civil
war going on at least in some parts of
Mexico.
So in Mexico you in some parts of Mexico
you have these drug cartels that are
very powerful and there there exists
essentially some kind of balance in some
countries in South America and Central
America between the government and the
drug cartel. And when it comes to these
drug cartels they're consumers
their consumers. Where are they located?
They're not located in Mexico or
Colombia or whatever. It's usually the
United States. The US is the customer
primary customer.
So in these nations like Mexico and
Colombia and so on there exists some
kind of balance some kind of equilibrium
homeostasis
between the government and the cartels
and looks like there is some
readjustment that's happening there.
Yeah. So it's let's see what the what
the latest news is like in Guadalara.
Uh Guadalara
let's see. So, okay, El Mencho was
killed in in a military operation. Looks
like he is a new fangled uh
uh what's his name?
Who was the great famous Colombian uh
drug dealer? I forget his name. Anyway,
uh Mexico cartel violence and so on. So,
yeah, this this violence happening
between the cartel, the cartel and the
the government. That's what's happening.
I was talking about Pablo Escobar here.
Pablo Escobar. Okay. Gapati says,
"Conspiracy theory for the day. Our
ancestors use the word Mletch to refer
to Malo worshippers.
Insane censorship is happening." Okay.
Uh look, this god called Malik,
this god is referred to in the Hebrew
Bible and he is referred to as a god
that is an evil god or something. And it
looks like this term mo it's simply a
placeholder for perhaps Yahweh or
perhaps mother god.
Now the Hebrew people their history is
about 3,000 years old. Okay 3,000 years
old or 3100 BC or wherever the 3100
1,100 AD or something is the first
mention of the
name Israel. Let's let's find out. Okay.
What's the oldest mention?
What is the oldest mention of the word
Israel in inscriptions?
So that's in Egypt I think. Okay.
Meahastil
Israel still 1208 BC.
So let's say the Jewish people, the
Israelite people existed let's say 800
years before that. So that's 2,000 BC.
Now when it comes to us,
our culture, it's 10,000 years old at
least. And the word Mletcha would have
existed long before this Malo or
whatever existed.
So it's an interesting idea. It's an
interesting theory, but most likely the
word Mletcha predates the Israelite
people. So, and perhaps it may have been
used to refer to Malok worshippers or I
don't know. I don't think I'm not sure
if Indians back in the day 1000 BC or
wherever would have ever taken note of
Malok worshippers or whatever. We were
trading with the with with Egypt.
We were trading with the Greece I
suppose to some extent with with the um
with the with Mesopotamia with Babylon
and so on with Assyria with with the
Sumerianss and so on. Um not with the
people in the Levant.
So I'm not sure if we would have really
bothered to
trans you know conf you know
transmogrify the name of this this uh
fringe god into a word for all
foreigners
all uh foreigners who did not practice
you know Indo-uropean
vic customs I think it's it's an
interesting theory but probably a little
far-fetched but interesting theory
nonetheless
Sergeant Skylon says it seems that the
Kadari engine has achieved 83 kon in
trust. What does this mean for our jet
engine program?
So let's see let's take a take a look at
the latest news about the cavary engine.
I also have heard that the after burn of
the wet thrust is is in excess of 80
kilon newton now. So let's see
cavary engine latest news
not calvary cavary. Okay.
Uh
cover engine latest news uh after burner
breakthrough revives the thing and so on
etc. So let's see what Z news has to say
about this. The cover engine rose back
with a big AI generated image reject. Uh
after burner breakthrough revives
India's 30-year dream inches closer to
combat rule. Um
so India will be partnering with Safo
and Rolls-Royce to develop a fighter jet
engines for the AMCA and so on. Amidst
this stuff,
DRDO has achieved what India has only
dreamed of for decades
is finally throwing. Yeah. Where's the
actual thing?
Um
what do we have? The cover engine has
not only not delivered that's old news
that's fine.
Uh it gives a thrust of 72 kilon newtons
but we need a thrust of 83 to 85 kilon
newtons.
According to the latest finally they're
coming to the point
according to the latest information the
cover engine after burner test success
reportedly displayed increased thrust of
81 to 83 konton. This happened after the
GTRE made significant technological
changes in the engine. Notably, the dry
thrust of the 49 kon cavary engine is
now nearly equal to the GE404
engine. The engine being used for the
air mass flow of cavary is higher. It's
78 kg/s versus 65 kg/s of the M882
engine developed by France. The only
drawback of the Cavary engine is its
weight which was around 300 kg extra
compared to the other rivals and now the
DU has reportedly reduced 100 kg in the
latest upgrades. This means that the gap
is now about 200 kilog.
Um
okay.
So the news is that now the cavary
engine the the dry thrust without the
after burner it's essentially the same
as the general electric F404 engine.
And now with the after burner the new
developments in the after burner
technology the coverage jet engine now
gives about 81 to 83 kon of wet thrust
which is essentially very very close to
what the American engine does. The
American engine goes up to 85. The
cavary is now at 81 to 83. Okay. And the
foreign engines are about 200 kilos
lighter than the cavary engine.
I think India should really take this
very seriously.
I mean, okay, it's a couple of hundred
kilograms heavier. Sure, I'm sure we can
shave down the weight further over time,
but we should not kill this program.
It's it's almost on par with foreign
engines. It's especially in terms of
thrust.
Some more tweaking with the afterburner
will give the same thrust as the
American jet engine.
The only issue is then uh the weight.
Well, that's okay. You have a jet engine
that's essentially on par with an
American engine. Now, it will obviously
need more testing. Let's not jump uh to
conclusions. It will need more testing,
rigorous testing and so on. Maybe on a
you know
uh various ways of testing it in actual
conditions. But it looks like they have
made significant progress. The other
question is what is the the life cycle
of the of the lifetime of the of the
engine? How long can it how many hours
can it be operational before it the
turbine blades have to replace and all
that? That also is a factor that that's
not being that's not being addressed in
this news report.
So there's multiple factors but it looks
like we have made significant progress
and looks like we are not far from
having a jet engine that's uh you know
on par with uh with leading jet engines.
So I think this is great. This is a
excellent work that that the GTR team
has done and maybe in two three years we
may have a jet engine that's on par with
the rest of the world. So with not not
the rest of the world but the leading
jet engines in the world. It's
fantastic. is great news and if this
happens then we could have multiple
families of jet engines in one the
cavary the indigenous cavary engine the
second one the engine we are developing
in collaboration with safh of France and
so on so that's fantastic that's great
news I would say kudos to the team
mac jvenu says when society falls
wars important right now I want
War VW
when society falls wars important right
now I want war view VW um I don't want
war is terrible sometimes some nation
needs war to to achieve certain
objectives yeah it's true sometimes you
need war no question about that but war
overall is terrible war causes
tremendous suffering war is horrific
from a humanitarian perspective
Yeah. Uh it's typically the the innocent
who who suffer the most in wars. So I
would not want war. Of course war is
inevitable. War eventually happens
sooner or later. That's true. But as far
as possible as civilized human beings,
we should not uh resolve problems
through war. So um yeah,
Mary Kane, good to see you ma'am. Mary
says, "Core architecture in
infrastructure of space stations will
rely on STEM disciplines. Private sector
could accelerate timelines. What would
you suggest for avoiding fund hoarding
string theory mafia?" Um
yeah, you're right absolutely that the
core architecture and infrastructure and
and technological
development of space stations and space
programs will obviously rely on the STEM
disciplines. Uh mainly physics, material
science
um
and obviously engineering the the broad
gamut of engineering disciplines. Uh so
that's what u space exploration and and
space stations will rely on. Now the
private sector obviously should be
involved in this. You can't leave
everything to the government. So for
example the US has has done a brilliant
job of of having this this hybrid model.
On on the one hand we have NASA which is
a government agency. On the other hand,
you have things like U Space X obviously
Loheed Martin and so many of these other
private uh players who are all working
in parallel par parallel
in in taking the American space program
further. Uh for example, the Arteimus
mission they have their own LVM or
whatever rocket it is which is not
developed by SpaceX. It's it's developed
by um Loheed Martin and whoever else.
Okay, let let's see the uh the Arteimus
program. Arteimus rocket.
Arteimus LVM rocket.
Okay, I'm mixing things up. Okay,
Arteimus rocket. Let's go for this. Oh,
something has happened. Postponed. So,
uh if you look at this Arteimus 2, the
Orion spacecraft, of course, you get the
Orion spacecraft. Now who has uh
built who has developed this spacecraft?
Uh SLS rocket. Okay. SLS rocket.
Uh it's used by NASA. Who has developed
it?
Okay. Looks like it's been developed by
developed by NASA. So the point is in
the US there's this great hybrid model
that you know you have Loheed Martin
various other other private players
including SpaceX the giant who all work
in parallel to in developing various
components of the of the jigsaw puzzle
needed for the US to be the global
superpower in space. So the private
sector obviously does accelerate
timelines. It's a great model to emulate
for India. But obviously India doesn't
have the sort of money, the kind of
money the US has. The Chinese on the
other hand have this uh
this program that's that until recently
was entirely government funded and
governmentr run. Now I suppose private
players must be uh participating in the
Chinese space program as well.
So uh India should also do this. Right
now we have ISRO and we have some space
startups but uh they haven't made any
major progress
for example sending a rocket into earth
orbit that sort of thing hasn't happened
as far as I know um
so yeah India needs to catch up now what
would I suggest for avoiding fund
hoarding string theory mafia so the
string theory mafia it's um that's in
academia that's in pure physics research
So
in in physics we we you know we seek to
discover this grand unified theory that
explains everything. The ground unified
theory that that is able to uh
to combine or merge general relativity
with with quantum mechanics and quantum
field theory because the two thus far
are are incompatible. The two best
theories that we have, the greatest
theories of all time, one is general
relativity, one is u quantum field
theory, quantum mechanics, these two
don't work together. For example, you
can't have quantum theory that works in
curved spacetime, you know, that sort of
thing. So, uh so the grand unified
theory is is this this great dream that
physicists have of unifying everything
into one consistent theory that explains
everything. And one candidate for that
is string theory. So that's all
theoretical physics. It's not applied
physics. It's not engineering. A lot of
and when when it comes to uh funding.
See there's a there's funding that's
given to pure science and there there's
funding that's given to engineering.
That's totally different funding. So
when it comes to the string theory
mafia, they have they have been able to
capture most of the funding that's
assigned to physics, pure physics
research, theoretical physics research.
And that's a problem. But it's not
hindering or hampering the space program
as such. Um so fund holding doesn't
happen when it comes to the space
program. I would say you know the
private sector as long as the private
sector gets more and more involved it's
going to be it's going to run much
leaner than NASA.
It's going to run much leaner than u any
any government agency. So my
my point is the private sector should be
involved as much as possible. That way
you know uh money won't be wasted and
all the operations will will run as lean
as possible.
Godliness says AI summit in Delhi had
some very impressive domestic AI models
but my concern is from chip designs to
manufacturing real hardware. All of this
is still in the hands of the US and we
saw no update on that. So India you are
right your concern is absolutely valid.
No question about that. So India is
India is doing good good work in in
terms of domestic models AI models.
Serwam is a great example of of uh u
very good um
indigenous model right so we have that
now the concern that you have is is the
hardware concern
so chip designs a lot of chip design is
done in India actually so we have the
brains we have the people with the
knowledge the knowhow and the experience
and the skills chip design but we don't
have any chip design companies in India
indigenous chip chip design companies
All these folks in India who work in
Bangalore, Hyderabad, wherever on chip
design, they work for these foreign
companies, American companies. So, uh
chip designs we can handle. We can do
chip design. I'm sure we have the people
who who have the knowhow. When it comes
to manufacturing, semiconductors and all
that. Well, all of that is still so in
in semiconductor manufacturing, you
first of all need to make those chips,
those silicon wafers. That's easy.
It's uh that's not that hard. Okay. But
then you have to etch the designs, etch
the circuits onto the silicon wafers and
that is very very specialized
technology. You need very complicated
very
expensive machines to do that. Uh these
machines are called photo lithography
machines and these machines are
manufactured by ASML. ASML controls
about 95% of the of the of the market in
this in this field. It's a Dutch company
and when it comes to manufacturing these
chips about 90% or around that that that
much of the market is controlled by
TSMC. It's a Taiwanese corporation.
So India is is now has now embarked on
its own semiconductor mission
and we are manufacturing chips of a
certain caliber. I mean it's not like
bullets of caliber but you get what I
mean. uh but we are about maybe a decade
or more behind the cutting edge uh chip
manufacturing that's done in the world
at least a decade behind so uh your
concern that's therefore is very valid
right um so this summit was an AI summit
it was not a semi it was not a
semiconductor summit so obviously there
will not have been any update on that
matter but uh that doesn't make your
concern any less valid so yeah India is
going to have to find uh solution
solutions to this issue, right? Uh not
just
uh being able to manufacture smaller I
mean I mean denser and denser chips but
the photoiththography technology that's
very important.
Kakashi says if China is compromised so
high up Jang Yushia how about India
because most minister's families kids
etc are in foreign countries in certain
think tanks
so in China
has cracked down on officials who have
relatives working who live in the US
let's see
China cracked down on officials with
relatives living in the United states.
Let's see. Uh yeah, they call them naked
officials.
Okay, the Chinese government calls these
people naked officials. Officials who
work for the Chinese Communist Party who
are in government and whose family
members reside abroad.
So the Chinese government is is placing
restrictions on these people and they're
pressurizing their relatives including
those in the US to return to China. And
if these officials are unable to
persuade their relatives to return to
China, then those officials are removed
from their positions,
maybe demoted significantly further down
where they don't really pose any any
issue or maybe they're completely
relieved of the duties. So these
officials in China are called naked
officials.
Uh it's not about Jang Yushia, it's
about other non-military people who are
in the Chinese Communist Party high up
in the government. Now when it comes to
India, um I don't think it's some big
secret that most Indian bureaucrats
whether they are high ranking
bureaucrats or lowranking bureaucrats,
they have children and and rel relatives
who live
in the west
children who study in western
universities mainly US yeah also UK and
when it comes to various Indian
ministers and so on the same story
applies some of them have children who
work
who study in a foreign country western
country some of them work in western
countries some of them have citizenships
of western countries some of them think
tanks whatever right so China considers
ers people like these officials like
these to be naked officials off
officials who are compromised and who
can compromise China. Is China right or
wrong to do this?
I think China is right to do this. See
during the days of the Roman Empire, the
Romans used to have this this this
policy
of keeping hostages.
So let's say you are the Roman Empire
and you have like 17 different vasals
who are all kings of other kingdoms that
you control.
So you have allowed those kings to
remain in power as long as they are your
vasals which means they will obey you.
But how do you ensure their obedience?
You tell these guys, these kings,
give me two of your sons and send them
to Rome. we will take care of their
education and everything. We will train
them to be the best possible kings or
whatever. Right? So every of these vasal
kings would have multiple sons who would
be studying in Rome, who would be
hostages in Rome.
That was the the way Roman the Roman
Empire handled vasals.
So this exact it's the exact same thing,
isn't it? Essentially,
it's the exact same thing. It's like
having hostages but
you know officials give up their family
members willingly voluntarily to be
hostages then they typically become
citizens in these countries. So um so so
the question you're asking is is India
compromised?
I I think I will let you all my viewers
draw the conclusions for yourselves. Is
India compromised
because of naked officials like what the
like the Chinese say.
Sam the Gamer says, "Aditya Menan's
alien invasion. Do Russia uni Russia US
unite?" Is this a question for me or
somebody else? If there's an alien
invasion, do Russia and the US unite? I
think it's unlikely even if there's an
alien invasion that Russia and the US
will will properly unite. Unlikely.
Amisha says, "If Afghanistan shared a
border with India, would relations be
hostile?
That's an interesting question. We could
ask we could ask this question in a
different way. If India shared a border
with Iran, would relations be hostile? I
think
one of the reasons why India has good
relations with Afghanistan is because we
don't have a shared border.
And even if we have a shared border, as
long as the border is properly
demarcated, there is no border dispute,
relations can be pretty stable and
pretty good,
right? Um
and as long as India is powerful enough,
all relations will be good. So um just
having a shared border with another
nation doesn't make the relations
hostile. As long as as as the border is
properly demarcated and as long as India
is powerful enough,
the relations will be fine.
Ganapati says maji restoration was the
original deep state sanatan marriage
that people like whoever talks about
okay I don't know what people talk about
um
the original deep state sanatan marriage
that some people talk about US won twice
against Japan 1853 and 1945 Modi is
trying to imitate in it in India insane
censorship looks like YouTube is not
allowing you to post certain things
that's why you use these uh this workar
around okay so the major restoration
um
it was all see it was not a marriage of
sanatan or Japanese sanatan with the
deep state
um in the major restoration okay the
major restoration did not go after
Shinto see the the original Japanese
religion or culture whatever you want to
call it is Shinto
and it is way more similar to Hinduism
than to Buddhism.
But eventually Buddhism reached Japan
via China also Hinduism reached Japan
via China and today and eventually all
these different practices and paths
synchretatized
in Japan. Now during the maj major
restoration 1853 onwards uh they tried
to portray Buddhism as a foreign
religion and they tried to eradicate
Buddhism from Japan that failed but
today in Japan Buddhism is kind of seen
as a foreign import. Yeah. Um but was
the major restoration
a marriage of Japanese sanatan practices
and the deep state?
I completely disagree with that
because if it was a marriage of deep
state with sanatan, let's say Shinto is
the Japanese sanatan. If it's a marriage
of deep state with Pinto, then how did
the Japanese soldiers practice so
much brutality and barbarity during the
Second World War? I don't think Shinto
allows that. Shinto is way more similar
to Hinduism
than to Buddhism. And Shinto doesn't
allow barbaric practices. All the things
that happen in naning and whatever
Shinto doesn't allow that
sort of brutal barbaric behavior. So I
don't see it as a marriage of uh deep
state with sanatan. The US won in 1853.
Sure they were able to influence Japan
into wiping out the samurai traditions
and becoming westernized.
It was a reaction to western
imperialism. The US did not trigger that
but whatever you want to say. Um 18 1945
definitely the US won by testing two
nuclear weapons in Japan. So you saying
that Modi is trying to imitate something
like this in India
some kind of major restoration in India.
Are you saying
so in the major restoration of an
element of foreign culture they tried to
remove it from Japan? Which element of
foreign culture is Modi trying to remove
from India? I wonder.
I don't see any of that.
Are we seeing some marriage of deep
state and sanatan in India?
Uh it doesn't work. Either the deep
state wins or sanathan wins. This there
cannot be any marriage between
between dharma and adharma.
Okay. So I I don't
can't be done. Can't be done.
Yasharati says screened out of AFS AFSB
today likely for obesity. What is AFSB?
Uh can discipline and creativity
painting I do coexist be using as excuse
that they can't pathetic me? Okay, I
don't know what is AFSB. Let me uh find
out.
AFSB.
No, no, no.
Okay. What is that? Air Force selection.
Oh, Air Force selection board.
Okay. So, you wanted to uh go for this
Air Force thing and you were screened
out of it because uh your weight is
okay. You're obese perhaps that's why.
Uh so the question you're asking is can
discipline and creativity coexist?
Oh absolutely.
Yes absolutely. Creativity thrives on
discipline.
So for example you are a painter. You
you do painting. That's a creative
endeavor.
But how do you do how do you become a
better painter?
Let's say you want to be a full-time
painter. How do you become a better
painter? How do you become better?
through discipline. So maybe as as a
dilont painter, as as as as a hobbyist
painter, you may paint maybe once a week
or maybe once a month or whatever. But
what if you force yourself to paint to
create one painting every single day for
the next year
anyhow every single day one painting you
to create. Let's say let's say doing
watercolors or acrylic or not oil
because that takes longer whatever.
So that way you're going to have to put
out more way more volume than than you
were doing before. And if you practice
so much creating one painting every day,
your skills improve exponentially
essentially. You see, discipline makes
makes creativity better. Creativity
thrives on discipline. So discipline and
creativity certainly can coexist.
Obviously discipline is not easy. It's
easy to speak about these things. It's
very hard to actually execute and
implement but certainly they can
coexist.
P Mahas Sager says Sar 10 major points
about how Gandhi was a British agent.
Okay, listen that's a highly
controversial topic. I have spoken about
this in the past. Okay. So, let me
instead of giving you a list of points
here, uh let me uh show you one of the
videos on my channel that uh I made a
couple of years ago and maybe you can
look into that. Give me a second. So,
let's put my channel on the on the thing
here. Okay. Gandhi.
So you search for Gandhi
and uh yeah this one this video on my
channel that you see here was Gandhi
really a Mahatma favoring British over
India
so you can watch that video it's about
21 or so minutes long and that video
will give you a reasonably you know good
idea of um of of the characteristics and
and and the life's work of Mr. Gandhi.
Prattana says, "Looking back at General
Wesley Clark interview in 2007 or so
about taking out seven countries in 5
years. It's scary. Everyone thought it
was a joke or something. So what
countries I I remember watching that
video long ago. He says Syria.
He says Libya.
He even mentioned Iran, doesn't he?
didn't he?
So, what are the nations he mentioned in
the in that interview? Let's let's find
out.
There was this interview by General
Wesley Clark in 2007 about US regime
changing seven countries in 5 years.
What countries were these?
Let's see.
Okay. Iraq done. Syria done. Lebanon in
work in progress. Libya done. Somalia,
well, I suppose work in progress. Sudan,
work in progress. Iran, right. Right.
So, yes, it was definitely not a joke.
It was very serious. No question about
that. It was very serious.
Okay. MKWN, etc. says, "Why did the
Arabs fail in India? Despite having the
same tactics as the Turks, like superior
archery, light and mobile cavalry,
retreats, fain retreats, and symmetric
warfare. The Arabs did not have anything
like the uh did not have any of the
archery skills the Turks had.
The Arabs weren't great at archery. They
were great at at they were good at sword
fighting. Um
and they did not really after the the
invasion by Muhammad bin Kasim, they did
not really follow up those invasions and
and try and make deeper inroads into
India. So Muhammad bin Kasim was able to
after the Arabic uh conquest of Persia,
they discovered this place called Sind,
right? And they wanted to see how far
they could penetrate into Sind. So
that's what Muhammad bin Kasim's job was
to try and invade Sind and it kind of
succeeded to a certain extent and that
was about it. After that the Arabs did
not really follow up too much. Um
so they were not persistent enough. The
Turks were persistent. They were
persistent for centuries. That's why the
Turks eventually succeeded. The Arabs
after taking Persia and launching some
foray, some expeditions into Sind they
stopped.
That was the issue.
Pratt Dhana says India's stray dog
problem. Does nobody like dogs in India?
If each family or person adopts one dog,
there will be no stray dogs or deceased.
Let's do this. So, there are two camps
in India. The more vocal camp is the one
that hates dogs. They want all dogs to
be massacred and genocided. The fact is
that the Indian dog is the world's
oldest breed of dogs. Which is the
world's oldest uh dog breed? Let's see
what Google say. Which is the world's
oldest dog breed or land race?
The Saluki
Greenland dog.
Uh dive deeper into AI mode. Let's see.
It's the Indian pariah dog, isn't it?
This is nonsense.
Okay. What about the Indian pariah dog?
Let's see what it says.
Yeah, it's the world. There we have it.
So, I don't know. It's contradicting
itself. AI, you know, that's what AI
does. AI still has a lot to do, a lot to
learn, lot lot of improvement to do. The
Indian stray dog is the world's oldest
and most primitive dog type. It is it's
the oldest land race of dogs in the
world and it's been coexisting with us
for at least 10,000 years. And today
Indians want to kill it off. A lot of
Indians want to kill it off.
Obviously there are issues, right? We
have this massive urbanization of India,
massive urban population. Dogs obviously
are there and u often you have these
issues where dogs attack human beings.
Another question is why do dogs attack
human beings? It's because dogs are
mistreated. It's because dogs are
brutalized. That's why dogs become
eventually cynical about humans and they
start attacking people. Dogs aren't The
Indian dog isn't naturally aggressive
towards humans. The Indian dog is
naturally very social and very friendly
towards humans. It is some people, some
lumpen elements in society who like to
be cruel to animals, who see dogs as an
easy target. They keep on doing this
with dogs and then eventually dogs get
fed up and then they start seeing all
humans as as predators and enemies.
That's what happens.
Yeah. Um
so what's the solution?
The solution is to
Well,
the solution isn't easy.
The good thing about the dogs have going
in their favor is that the government of
India is very inefficient.
Otherwise they would have genocided dogs
long ago. Recently they were even going
after pigeons. Pigeons are actually
victims. You know that pigeons used to
be they used to work for humans. They
used to be domestic birds. Humans used
pigeons. Pigeons originally were wild
birds. Humans captured them,
domesticated them and used them for
transmitting messages.
And then after after we we had the
telegraph and other the technology
coming in, we just abandoned the
pigeons. And that's why pigeons live in
urban areas, but they are no longer that
domestic anymore. And now humans hate
pigeons as well. When we use them, then
we abandon them. And there's a lot of
people in India who hate dogs.
What's the solution? I'm I'm I don't
know. In my opinion, dogs have as much a
right to exist as humans, and they have
always coexisted with humans, at least
the past 10,000 years,
right?
Um
so I don't know what's what the solution
is. The solution is for humans to be, I
would say, less cruel to animals, less
cruel to dogs.
And uh
and yeah, if there are dogs that are
aggressive, well, I suppose they have to
be dealt with. Of course, you can't have
dogs
uh biting humans and children and all
that. So those dogs need to be dealt
with in whatever way, whatever
unfortunate way, but overall dogs, they
are part of our society. Yeah.
Pratar Dhana says, "You are no longer
shadowbanned. Subs increased finally."
Um
the stocks are again once again slowly
slowly slowly going down once again. So
uh the policy of of YouTube continues
towards this channel. A few days ago,
four five days ago, my subs were I don't
know 951,300
something. Now it's once again 951,260
something. So it's slowly trickling down
once again.
And and so I mean look, it's not my
platform. It's a foreign platform. They
can do whatever they want. And that's
what they're doing to the channel. I
mean, it's it's stuck between 949 to
951K for the ne last almost 1 year. That
is so unnatural. That's so artificial.
What can I say? Whatever. We carry on.
If you can't control it, don't worry
about it.
Virtually present says Safong engine
deal is still a awaiting final CCS
approval. Has been the past 6 months.
timelines have already shifted further
into the future. Thoughts pure
bureaucracy to blame. Big fan by the
way. Thank you. Well, thank you so much,
sir. This is the way things are done in
India. I mean, we have this U MRFA
program, right? The MRFA U program.
Let's see this
India MRFA program.
Multi-roll fighter aircraft program. So,
Let's ask a different question. Okay.
When
was was
the
um initiated?
Initiated. Let's see.
Not 2.0. 1.0.
1.0.
That's not 2019, man. It was about 20,
30 years ago.
MRCA, is it MRCA? What's MRCA? MMRCA.
Okay. So, what's the history?
What's the background?
Okay. It's going to take Okay, it's
going to take too long for me to look
into this, but it's about 20 years old
and it's still not finished, right? we
still have this requirement. So in India
everything is super bureaucratic this
tremendous red tape
everything takes way too long way too
long and by the time you actually
implement something it's become obsolete
that's how it's done in India now my
question is why has the government of
India the Narendra Modi government not
resolved these issues why do things
still take so long
I think it's a little too late to keep
blaming the previous governments right
for the problems we have in India today.
Um
so if you have decided to go ahead with
the software engine please sign the deal
and let's get going right let's start
doing the engineering work.
Um let's let's see what's the what's the
status
what is the status of the India saf
engine deal has the contract been signed
let's see
they have finalized the landmark
agreement um etc etc
the deal is in its final stages moving
towards cabinet committee on security
status clearance. I don't know what sort
of system India has and why it is like
this
extremely frustrating and extremely
inefficient and why has the government
not been able to solve these things
after all these years. Why do things
take so long?
Is this how you become a superpower and
visual guru? No, this is how you become
a vasal.
DSOTM says dark side of the moon. It
says undergraduate computer science
student paper got accepted at e access
uh bleep professor just put his name. Me
and my colleague did all the hard work.
When is change happening?
See when I when I say that the Indian
education system is corrupt. This is
what I mean by that.
Some people get upset when I when I
criticize the education system. Oh no,
we have the new education policy 2020 or
whatever it is is going to solve all the
problems. It's not going to solve this
problem. Your new education policy.
So this
person, I don't know his or her real
name, but
let's say it's a he. So his he's an
undergraduate computer science student.
um his paper the paper he and and his
colleague worked on it got accepted at E
what's E let's see
what is E
institute of electrical and electronics
engineer engineers okay so your paper
got accepted uh in in their I suppose
journal or whatever and your professor
put his name on the paper like he is the
author
and he did not allow you and your
colleague to even be the secondary and
second and third authors. So this is
what happens in India and if a student
dares to speak up against the professor
they'll be failed. They will not get
their degree that's why students keep
quiet no matter what happens. This is
the rot the garbage the corruption
in the Indian education system and
that's what I have been speaking about
for years now. that this needs to be
reformed. Has anything been been
reformed? Anything at all? What is the
government of India doing? It has had
enough time to at least get rid of some
of this corruption. Nothing.
So when is the change happening? I would
say the change is not happening. The the
government is doesn't want to change any
of this.
That's where we are.
Okay. Okay, Pratarana says my theory it
seems the overlord allows India to make
technologies but at a condition that
India won't dare compete with them and
use theirs instead.
So see India has always loved you know
doing the technology demonstrations. In
1974 India tested a nuclear weapon in
Pokran 1 and then India said this was
simply a technology demonstration. We
are a peaceful nonviolent
useless nation. We have we don't like
violence. We don't like nuclear weapons.
We just want to show that we have the
technology. Now we will take this
nuclear weapons technology. we'll put it
on the shelf over here and we'll sleep
about it. So from 1974 to 1998, India
took that technology it had developed
and just put it on the shelf in cold
storage.
That's what India did.
So right now we are developing some AI
technologies, some AI models or
whatever. Private companies are doing
that. I I wonder what problems these
private companies are facing actually in
doing all of this. But some of them are
succeeding. Uh
so overall what happens in India is that
you know when there is an overlord a
Kaiser Caesar somewhere okay then they
are okay as long as India develops some
technologies and uses them as technology
demonstrators but doesn't commercialize
the technology
you know full-fledged commercializ
commercialization.
So there are so many pieces of news that
come out that India has developed some
um anti-mar malarial thing or some
anti-tuberculosis thing but does it ever
get commercialized? No, nothing. We just
talk. We have our scientists do the
work, our engineers do the work and then
it never gets commercialized. Maybe the
commercial maybe the technology that
gets somehow transferred somewhere else
by maybe hypothetically some some some
bureaucrat or whatever. Who knows? Who
knows?
So the overload wants India to will
tolerate India developing technologies
and then perhaps transferring these
technologies to them or maybe not
commercializing them. So essentially
India should not compete. You do your
technological demonstrations, you do
your homework and school work and all
but don't compete with us. And at the
end of the day when it comes to
widespread adoption, use American
technologies. That's what's happening in
India in the AI summit. That's what the
Americans told us that we want you to
use our AI stack. Use our AI products.
We see you as customers and customers
only. Don't try to become competitors.
Remain customers. Remain a nice good
boy. And India seems to be going along
that path right now.
Sam the Gamer says, "Can
Sam's surfaceto-air missiles like
Nasam's S400 compensate for low fighter
squadron strength? Is China's hostility
to neighbors beneficial or a blunder?"
Science episode next.
Can surfaceto-air missiles compensate
for low fighter squadron strength? Well,
when it comes to
it, it can. It can.
So what do you use fighter planes for?
See, India only has fighter jets, right?
India doesn't have long range strategic
bombers or any any of those things.
India has historically operated for
example on aircraft carrier C harriers
and Mig 29s. The fighter planes, fighter
interceptors or whatever. Then Sukhoys,
Sukoy 30, 30 MKI fighter planes. These
are heavy fighter planes but still
fighter planes. We have the Jaguar, we
have the Mirage, Mirage 2000, we had the
MIG21 fighter interceptor, we have the
Tjas similar role.
So what is the role of these aircraft?
Mainly taking out the enemy's aircraft
and secondly doing some some light
bombing.
Light bombing. So you send a sorty of
let's say five fighter planes and they
will take out the enemies fighter planes
and then you can do some light bombing
and that sort of thing. maybe take out a
few radars, maybe um you know hit a few
uh installations, do some cratering of
some runways and so on. Light bombing,
the heavy bombing, you know, hardcore
bombing is done by strategic bombers
that India doesn't have. So if you have
if if you if you don't have sufficient
fighter planes, you certainly can use
missiles to do exactly the same thing.
So missiles can certainly compensate for
low fighter squadron strength
and not just surfaceto-air missiles but
other missiles too. So SAMS can
essentially take out the enemy's fighter
planes like the Akash missile and so on.
They can take out a demified planes and
then you can use cruise missiles like
the Brahos
and other kinds of missiles even drones
and so on to do the job of bombing the
installations of the enemy just like you
would do with fighter planes and you you
do it in a risk-free manner because
you're not risking human lives now. So
missiles can certainly compensate for uh
you know low fighter squadron strengths.
China's hostility to neighbors
beneficial or a blunder? Well, it
depends if it China is strong enough.
It's definitely beneficial for China.
Otherwise, it's a blender.
Science episode. Okay, I will consider
that. I'll maybe put out a poll. Do
people actually want a science episode?
I there's no point doing it if like 20
people are watching, right?
Uh Sanatani Dwanch says historical
origin of gurj who are usually katrias
and whether similarities with juts and
rajuts comes with shared ancestry.
I'm not sure about the historical origin
of the guras.
Um
they definitely are a warrior cl warrior
community. Today you have gourjs who are
who are Muslims in Pakistan and gurjas
who are Hindu in India right
similarities with Jats and Rajputs. Jats
and Rajput see Jats are farmers but
historically warriors. Rajuts are
Chhatria's warriors but royalty. Rajputs
are descendants from kings descended
descendants of kings. So um but what's
the origin of the gur?
Um I'm not really sure. I mean there's a
whole state in India named after
gurujars gujarat right
so are all gujati descended descendants
of gurj I'm not really sure
gurjars gurjaresh
uh
gurjard used to be much much more than
gujarat actually but I am not 100% clear
about the origin of the gurj
yeah can't say right now maybe I look
into
Gapati says wrong spellings ahead on
purpose.
Statue of Turtor
founder
OD Swatra party who wanted India to
fight
Anglo-Saxon wars. See Rajak Gopalachari
unveiled in Rashapati Bhan. I have to do
this to avoid censorship. Why would
YouTube censor this stuff? Why? I don't
get it. So statue of
curator curator
f
founder of sautrauta part sautantra
party who wanted to fight ind who wanted
India to fight Anglo-Saxon wars
let's see what is okay I'm not I don't
know the history of this gentleman
uh Swatantra party
swatantra party
uh Satantra party in English
okay let's see uh Swatantra party and
who is the founder of S Raja Gopalachare
S Raj Gopalachari
uh who is this gentleman he's last
governor general of India I'm sure he
was a Gandhian yes was he Gandhian let
me search for Gandhiian
Gandhian principles of course. Yeah. So
this is a Gandhian person as founder of
the Satantra party or whatever. Has his
statue been unvealed in uh Rashtraati
Bhawan
statue? Oh fascinating.
Okay. So this person's uh this fantastic
gentleman's statue has been unveiled in
uh Rashtapad. Now did he want India to
fight Anglo-Saxon wars? I don't know
about that. I don't know the history of
this particular gentleman. I've heard
the name I've heard the name associated
with India's freedom struggle struggle
which means India's nonviolent freedom
struggle. But I don't know his history.
I don't know what he did, what he did
not do um and what he his actual
contributions were to India's uh freedom
struggle. So I don't know but clearly he
seems to be a very well
great person because his statue is there
in the Rashtraati now must be a great
person.
Prattadhana says Ashwave coins of Guptas
is equal to Harpan unicorn seal. Um
I I have not thought about the
similarity. Let's see.
Ashwa made the coins of Gupta Empire.
No, no, no. Ashwamed. Hey AI, come on.
Ashwamed coins of the Gupta Empire.
Let's see. Um um ah very interesting.
Yes.
So this is clearly a a horse.
Yeah. Uh so this is the depiction of
horses and ashwa possibly on coins of
the Gupta Empire.
Um okay. So we have the horse depicted
here. Now let's see.
Oops.
Harapan unicorn seals.
Does kind of look similar, doesn't it?
Does kind of look similar.
And I'm not sure if these are actual
unicorns. Maybe it's the two horns seam
sideways which make it makes it seem
like one. But these are clearly boine
animals. These are clearly bulls. These
are clearly not horses.
That much is clear as at least to me.
This is clearly a bull. It's not a
horse, right? It's the it's the Indian
bull, the zebu bull. So, uh it's
definitely not a horse. So there is
similarity for sure but not sure if the
bull depiction has any connection with
the ashwa yagna because the ashwa yagna
was centered around the ashwa the horse.
So similar imagery but probably
different different meanings and
functions.
Okay,
Shibamhat Shibam Chhataraj says some say
in AI will automate India's services
others say that using American models
this present growth in MNC's with
collabs with US India is India safe
what's my thoughts
um see what's what are my thoughts about
this first of all India is not a
technologically sovereign nation India
depends on other nations primarily the
west primarily the US poor technology.
India
has the benefit of all these free
services like Google search, Gmail and
all and so on. These are American
services. But the price we pay is that
we give them all our data. So India is a
technological vasal of the US. Okay.
Now even the US is not 100%
technologically sovereign because of
various reasons. That's why I don't use
technological sovereignty as one of the
parameters in in calculating the overall
sovereignty of a nation. But it is
definitely a huge huge red flag for
India that India is very very behind in
all these technologies. Now when it
comes to services,
AI can automate a lot of things. No
question. Now right now the rate of
adoption, the level of adoption of AI in
the world is pretty low. maybe 20 30% of
the world's population must be using uh
let's say free AI services like the free
tier of chart GPD the free tier um of
chart GPT or whatever else maybe a small
percentage maybe 5% must be using paid
services AI services and maybe less than
1% will be using you know using AI to
build something real so AI adoption is
still you know the world is still far
behind AI adoption
But eventually a lot of services can be
automated. Uh maybe you know a lot of
government services, a lot of government
bureaucratic work can be automated. Um a
lot of stuff can be automated. When it
comes to India's IT exports, AI can
essentially eventually replace that
eventually. Not yet. Not yet. We're
still not there yet. But it will happen.
And there are people who who are saying
it will never happen. They have no idea
what's coming.
Um
so um and India is using mostly American
models right chat GPT is American um
Claude is American um Gemini is American
so on most Indians use chat GPT so
you're using American models you're
giving them your data you're training
them on more of your data that's the
sort of thing so the question you're
asking eventually is is India safe no
India is not safe India is not safe in
this India needs to have its own
frontier models, its own sovereign
models. The sovereignty is a words that
that's that's thrown around very very
easily these days. In the AI summit,
there was this all these hoardings with
sovereign AI, sovereign AI everywhere.
But then in front of the hoarding, the
Americas are saying use the American AI
stack and that's what India is
essentially doing right now. Sovereignty
also has become kind of a slogan these
days in India. Everything is a slogan.
India is not safe. India is definitely
not safe in this.
Gapati says, "Why do so many Indian
nationalists seem to simp for Israel?
Israel and Pakistan are more closely
allied than people think. Pull support
SAR is embarrassing.
Um why do so many Indian nationalists
simp for Israel?"
Well, Israel is a nation that is worthy
of a lot of admiration for all they have
achieved despite being so small and
despite being surrounded by so many
enemies, despite despite all the odds,
Israel stands there and Israel is the
most powerful nation in West Asia. That
is certainly worthy of admiration. I
will not discuss the what's going on in
Gaza and all that. That's a different
matter. So many Indians see that and
they find that inspirational and they
wish that India could do could have a
similar approach. Of course, India
doesn't have a similar approach despite
being a gigantic nation. India doesn't
have a similar approach. So lots of
Indians wish that it was the case. Um
another thing is that lots of Indians
perhaps simp for Israel because Israel
has a lot of Muslim enemies. That could
be another factor perhaps and we are
also surrounded. We have also been under
Turk Islamic occupation for for a long
time. We have Pakistan as as as an
adversary and so on. So maybe they see
something similar
in Israel, a similar kind of situation
for Israel and they admire the way
Israel is respond is is responding and
has traditionally responded to these
threats as opposed to India. Right?
India is a soft state. India, Israel is
a hard state. So that's why many Indian
nationalists seem to simp for Israel.
But and lots of Indians have the Israeli
flag on their on their on their social
media profiles and all that. You know,
it is from the way I see it, the only
flag that you should have on your
profile is your own flag. And it's fine
to admire other nations, but you never
give anybody your full support
unconditionally. and the only nation
that you should support fully is yours.
Um,
and then there are some people who pro
probably could be on the payroll of
certain countries. That's also a
possibility. So,
Teen Talks says, "Does Ragnar does
Ragnar Lothbach Lobbrock really excited
existed? Did he really exist is what
you're asking. Did Ragnar Lutbrock
really exist? Wikipedia says that he was
a semi-leendary king, a combination of
many kings. Was he related to Leif
Ericson who discovered America?
Well, we know for sure that there was
this great heathen invasion of England.
Okay, let's let's find it.
Which was supposedly done by the sons of
Ragnal.
Great heathen invasion of England.
Let's see the great heathen army. So
this was an actual invasion of England.
This is a historical fact. A massive
coalition of scientists Scandinavian
Vikings. Um
and it was led by Ivar the Boneless, Uba
and Halan Ragnaran.
And these are supposed to be the sons of
one single person, Ragnar Lot.
um
the tale of Ragnar's sons. So it looks
like this person Ragnar Lro did exist.
Um maybe there's no historical hard
evidence of him but that way there is no
historical hard evidence of Jesus Christ
also.
Right?
So I'm not sure why Ragnar Lot is
considered to be a semi-leendary king.
We have the great heathen army that
invaded England and transformed England.
This was the beginning of the Viking age
when the Vikings went from being
small-time raiders to full-time
occupants of England, northern England,
northern the British Isles at least, and
uh the beginning of Danlow, you know,
the Danish occupation of England, which
permanently transformed England, by the
way. and uh and the
the leaders of this coalition of Vikings
were the sons of Ragnar Lothrock. So I'm
not sure why he is considered to be a
semi-leendary king. Um there may be some
good reasons for it but I'm not sure.
Was he related to Leif Ericson who
discovered America? I am not aware of
any connection between Ragnar Lothrock
and Leif Ericson. I'm not aware of any
connection between the two.
Karan says, "I think there were multiple
intricate domes in the Arabic world like
Alabakirya mosque, Ashrafia mosque, Aya,
Madrasa, Mudafar mosque, Yemen, Albbaki
cemetery way before Taj Mahal
etc. All right. So, thank you very much
for your um comment.
Rohanbidi says why did the Naji
Nazis why did the Nazis choose the haken
koit as their insignia and is its
significance to the Hindu swastik only
coincidental
so this symbol the swastik which we call
the swastik it's a symbol of
auspiciousness it's a very
holy very positive very auspicious
symbol right isn't it that's what it is
for us in our culture It's also the same
thing in Japan. For example, if you go
to Japan,
Japan, Google Maps, swastika.
So if you see Google maps in Japan,
you're going to see swastikas for
Japanese temples, for either Buddhist
temples or Shinto temples. Can you see
this? you will see swastikas the rivers
swastika
on Google maps which denote um Japanese
temples so even for Japan it's a symbol
of holiness auspiciousness and so on now
what about Europe I'm talking about
pre-Christian Europe okay
gamadian
okay doesn't know how to interpret that
the AI
or let us uh
do the search again.
So there is this thing called the
gamadian which is once again the same
thing the swastika it's kind of a
truncated swastika if you see here and
that's a European swastika what about
the fiflot
okay phil
once again this is another word for the
swastika
so in Europe it was not called the
swastika it was called the gamarian and
the field for
okay And you have you will see swastikas
in in in
in churches. You will see swastikas in
monasteries. You will see swastikas all
over Europe. And this was a
pre-Christian symbol in Europe. And once
again, even in Europe before
Christianity, you had the same old
religion, the old Indo-Uropean religion
which was very closely connected to the
Vic religion.
And that's why in Europe also you had
this symbol that was a symbol of
auspiciousness and positivity and so on.
So it's a very ancient symbol. It's a
symbol of auspiciousness.
Now why did Hitler choose the hacken the
the hooked cross? So the hooked cross is
the tilted symbol. It's got a red
background and a black black thing.
Right? The symbol is in black. The haken
crates. Let's see what the hacken crates
looks like. Haken crates.
Oh, come on.
Haken Cro,
the hooked to cross. So, this is the
evil Nazi symbol, the Haken Cro. This is
the one. Um, so it's different from the
swastika, right? It's got this red color
and it's got the black black thing and
all. So it obviously is based on the
gamadian the the field forth the
swastika etc. So why did the Nazis
choose this? Because they wanted to have
a symbol of their own that that was
different from
the communist symbol. Okay,
communist symbol hammer and sickle.
See this is the hammer and sickle of the
communists. The Nazis wanted to have
their own thing. So that's how they
somehow came up with the field for the
with the with the hacken cros have their
own symbol that can oppose the communist
thing. That sort of thing.
Gapati says most uh many people think
Washington is the capital of the deep
state. Wrong. My analysis points out
that Frankfurt is the real capital of
the deep state.
Wanted to give explanation but super
super chat is censoring me. Are you
talking about the Frankfurt School of
Economics
which could possibly have a connection?
Let's see.
Frankfurt School of Economics.
Yes. Oh, sociology and critical theory.
Ah, is very interesting. The Frankfurt
School is a school of thought in
sociology in critical theory institute
for Yes. Who are these fine gentlemen?
um whoever they are.
So uh is this what you are perhaps
talking about?
So maybe it has some connection with
what some people call the deep state
perhaps.
Noise says professor showed us discovery
of India. So I asked the basis of the
Arian invasion theory and why this
theory is thought of as history. He did
what they all do. Look down. Ignore this
professor. These professors will always
forever be stuck in those little desk
jobs and they will not matter. Forget
about that. Forget about it. Don't worry
about what the professor thinks. India's
professors are are trash.
Not all. Most of them. Most of India's
professors are they don't deserve to be
professors, right? They're still hung up
on ancient outdated theories and whatn
not. These people don't matter. So don't
feel bad about this professor looking
down upon you. How does it matter?
You're going to go on and do a lot of
things in your in your life and that
professor is going to remain stuck where
he is. Ignore the professor to hell with
him.
Prayumar says is the whole point of
education to raise standards. So the
point of education that's a good good
question. Great question. What's the
point of education? It's not simply and
only raising standards. The point of
education
is to acquire skills.
The point of education is to acquire
the ability to think in the right ways,
to think critically. The ability to is
to acquire the ability to solve any
problem that life throws at you.
The point of education of an education
system is to give society every year a
new batch of highly capable, highly
skilled, highly confident young people
who can go and contribute to society and
change the world for the better. That is
the point of education. Now the Indian
education system does the exact opposite
of everything I just said. That's the
problem.
Teen Talk says Greek and Normiths are
inspired by us. Then why are their
stories packed with adultery and gore
without any philosophy like our
opishations or Gita? Well, that's the
reason we called these people matchas,
right? They may have originally been
like us, maybe originally of Indian
origin, but they went away. They went
far away. They they lost in the battle
of the 10 kings and over time they
strayed away from the path of the Vedas
of the Vic principles, Vic Vic
practices. So they retained their old
language which over time changed. They
retained their own culture. They
remember the remember the old gods but
their gods became twisted eventually
over time
a gore gore is a different story but
adultery and all those things yeah for
example Zeus
Zeus and his adultery all the time and
that sort of thing so that's why they
are called mletches right understand
that
when a population moves away from the
ancestral land and moves away thousands
of kilometers on foot, on horses,
whatever, and stays away for centuries
permanently, maybe thousand years, their
lifestyle changes, right? That lifestyle
naturally, inevitably changes.
So that's fine.
King Ritik the Great says, "Super chat
sessions on Monday due to World Cup."
Yeah, yesterday there was some cricket
match. I heard that we didn't do very
well in the cricket match. Anyway, I
thought, why compete with a cricket
match in the world cup? That's why I
moved this session to Monday. Probably
this coming weekend I shall not do that.
I don't know if there's a cricket match
this coming Sunday but this coming
Sunday I'll do the live stream on Sunday
itself. So so that's the reason why I
have I'm doing this on Monday at this
time.
Mac 4 Ju says beef eating history of
Kerala Hindus when did it start? I have
no idea. I have not studied the history
of the beef eating Kerala Hindus. I have
no idea. In Kerala we had the highest
standards. The Kerala Hindus were had
probably higher standards than Hindus in
the rest of the country and today they
eat beef. See how far we have fallen. I
have no idea when it started. It
probably had something to do with the
introduction of foreign cultures,
foreign people and foreign religions
into India. Probably something to do
with that. Probably something to do with
Christian missionaries.
Probably something to do with some other
religion. Who knows? I I don't know. I
don't want to speculate but I haven't
studied this.
Angut gal says do you think there will
be war in 2026 or propaganda and I've
heard of professor Jang and do you think
Dawkins is right on God and I don't I
mean how many questions do you have?
Okay I haven't studied I haven't watched
professor Jang yet. I've been many
people have been recommending it. I
haven't got around to watching professor
Jang.
Uh so I can't say about that. Will there
be war in 2026? I think a war on Iran by
the US seems pretty inevitable right
now.
Yeah. Which could happen in the next few
days if not tomorrow morning or tonight.
Who knows?
Um
why do I say it's inevitable? It's
almost inevitable. Why? Why do I say
that? Because the US
is making maximalist demands on Iran.
Right now there are some negotiations
happening. The US wants Iran to
demilitarize, disarm itself and
denuclearize.
So if Iran gives up its weapons, gives
up its nuclear program and gives up its
missiles, then what happens next? Next
it is a setting duck and then the
Americans can return with Israel and
wipe out Iran. Once you are defenseless,
the Americans are essentially saying
that Iran should make itself
defenseless.
Now, do you think Iran can accept that?
Of course, Iran can't accept that.
So, if Iran won't accept what the
Americans and Israelis say because the
Israeli position is essentially
identical to the American position. So,
if Iran doesn't accept what America
says, then Trump has already moved all
this equipment to West Asia.
About 40 to 50% of the deployable air
force assets of the US have apparently
been moved to West Asia. Two entire
aircraft carrier strike groups have been
deployed there after spending so much
money deploying all this military force
there. If Trump
doesn't get what he wants from Iran,
then he has essentially painted himself
into a corner. And that's why I say it's
likely that the the Americans will will
target Iran, will will strike at Iran
and that will lead to war because for
Iran this is an existential threat. It's
not like the 12-day war that happened
last year. So I think it's very likely
there's going to be war
that America imposes on Iran and that
could happen any time now. That's what
it looks like. Uh I have no idea about
Dawkins and his views on God.
probably atheism or some something like
that. Uh my opinion is that atheists are
the biggest idiots in the world.
I am not an atheist.
I probably am some kind of agnostic.
But you know what atheism means? If
you're an atheist, you're making the
statement making you assert if you're an
atheist, you're asserting that you know
that in the entire universe there is no
god.
I mean, who the hell do you think you
are that you know exactly what's going
on in the entire universe?
And do you even know what's beyond the
universe?
So, it's like
I mean it it makes no sense. It's like
an ant saying I know everything about
the planet Earth, right? That sort of
thing. Um, so
if you have any sense, you you can't be
an atheist. But Mr. Dawkins, professor
Dawkins apparently has understood ex
everything about the universe and that's
why he has made this claim. So I find
that really stupid.
So that's what I that's what my views
are on atheism. It's it's
low intelligence behavior atheism.
Uh Pratam Medar says it seems like
Mexico has better standards than India.
uh the El Mancho was the next Pablo
Escobar of Mexico and they took him out.
But when it comes to India, why have we
not taken out Haf say the felity? So
yeah, Haf say the felity is in Pakistan.
El Mancho was in Mexico.
That's why the government of Mexico took
him out.
El Mancho was not in the United States
or in some neighboring country of
Mexico.
You see,
of course, India is a much more
is a much larger country than Mexico,
much more powerful country than Mexico.
But India, India has different
standards. So
yeah,
Shashank says, "Why did the Delhi blast
disappear online? Is it natural or by
design? Is it sc isn't it scary that
something so serious can just vanish
from public memory?"
Public memory has always been like this.
Public me memory is always fickle.
Today's today most people won't remember
what India was like 20 years ago.
How
how far behind India was compared to
today 20 years ago. How bad the
governance and mismanagement was. People
won't remember that
public memory is extremely fickle.
Yeah. So that's how it is. I mean in a
state let's say you have a state
election coming up people in that state
won't even remember how good or how bad
the previous government was five six
seven years ago
right
so public memory is very fickle people
simply don't think people simply don't
remember things that's how it is
Angad Gal says if you watch football who
do you support minus Bayern Munich who
do you think will win win UCLA in this
2020 World Cup and sir, do you think
Iran is nukes or just USA hypes? Hype
okay like I don't watch football anymore
these days. I I certainly try and watch
the World Cup at at least the the
important matches whenever it happens.
Um there was a time when I used to watch
a lot more sports these days I don't do
that do it that much. So um I don't know
even know who plays for whom anymore
which EPL team or whatever. Uh UCL.
What's UCL?
Okay, UFAF Champions League. I am not
sure who will win the UFA Champions
League. I'm not following it. I am
totally out of it. So, I don't know. Uh
the last time I had I paid any actual
attention to to to
club football was when the Ori was
playing for Arsenal and Rudan Roy was
playing for Manchester United. That's a
long time ago. Uh now, nowadays I have
no idea who's playing for whom. So I
don't know Bayern Munich was a good used
to be a good team. I'm sure it still is.
How is AC Milan these days? They're the
three flying Dutchmen back in the day.
Marco Vanbastan, Frank Reichard,
Rudulit. That's a long time ago once
again. So uh I don't know who will win
the UF Champions League. This T20 World
Cup looks like India is going to face a
lot of difficulty in qualifying for the
next round. It looks like that because
India has lost yesterday apparently to
South Africa and apparently the net run
rate is very bad for India. So India may
not qualify for the next round it looks
like. So in that case who wins? My bet
is on Zimbabwe.
I would love for Zimbabwe to win or
Afghanistan to win if India doesn't get
through or even the West Indies. The
West Indies need some need a need a
revival don't they? The Aussies are out.
England. I don't know what they're
doing. So yeah, I I have no idea who's
going to win this T20 World Cup. I hope
it's India, of course, but I don't know.
It looks unlikely perhaps. Uh do I think
Iran has nukes? I think they have
sufficient file material, highly
enriched uranium for at least a few
nuclear weapons. I'm sure by now, but
they seem to be too scared to actually
operationalize their nuclear deterrent.
So I think they have sufficient file
material for at least a few warheads.
Aam senpai says big fan of yours for
four years. Thank you so much sir. Thank
you so much from Marunach. Now unity in
diversity seems fake in Delhi. Be
diverse but behave north. Slurs like
massage pala momo security I'm fluent in
Hindi. How much more to prove ourselves?
It's it's terrible. It's terrible that
that people from India's far east etc
have to still face these problems. The
reason for this is that a lot see the
root cause once again is the Indian
education system. If we are taught from
childhood
that we have these states that are part
of our country and that's what the
people of these places look like and
they are the same as us. They are not
these stereotypes like massage, pal,
momo, whatever.
So that's the job, the role of the
education system to educate people
properly so that by the time they're
they're grown up, they know exactly what
the northeast is and what people from
the northeast are like and they don't,
you know, resort to stereotypes.
And we have these slogans like national
integration and all
but uh there are parts of India where
the where where it's very hard for
people to come and visit the rest of
India.
I wonder how many people from Arunachal
have even visited other parts of India.
Must be pretty difficult. Must be pretty
hard I'm sure.
So that's how it is. India has all these
problems.
So uh you know it's terrible that these
such slurs are used. I'm sure a lot of
people don't use it, but still you will
have some people who who do that.
So, um the the point is you don't have
to prove yourself to anybody.
Don't ever feel the pressure to prove
yourself to anybody. You be you. And if
somebody uses slurs, then just ignore
them. Move on. Those people, they don't
matter.
Ignore them.
So yeah,
this shouldn't exist in today's India
and it is a failure of the education
system, the a failure of the government
that these issues still exist.
Quick S says going Germany for an MS in
computer science. How to maximize return
on investment? Okay, how to maximize
your return on investment? First of all,
get your degree with with high marks or
whatever it is. Secondly, get yourself I
mean you have to determine what is it
that you desire as ROI.
What do you desire? What is your desired
return on the investment? Whatever it
is, if you get it, you have maximized
your ROI. If you don't get it or if you
get only get it only partially, then you
haven't maximized your ROI. So if you
are an individual, you're going outside
of the country for your you're going to
Germany which means you you're you or
your parents have spent a lot of money
in doing this right unless you are going
on a scholarship which is pretty hard to
obtain. So assume you've your parents
have spent a lot of money. So the first
ROI is that you need to quickly get a
job somewhere a high paying job such
that you can repay your parents as soon
as possible
and uh so yeah a highpaying job wherever
it is probably not in India in India the
jobs aren't as high paying as in the
west so how do you maximize ROI you get
a job somewhere maybe in Germany maybe
somewhere else in some other country and
uh that's one way of looking at maximal
ROI
uh so you get a you get your degree and
you get a good job and
then so so that that essentially is your
ROI as far as I see in brief.
Skylight says been researching FRBs
with a group of scientists fast radio
bursts. H interesting basically we want
to see if we can find an under 100
meghertz using the LWA data sets. Uh, do
you have any insights that could help us
in this endeavor?
No, I am not into fast radio bursts. I
am into pure pure physics. Pure
theoretical physics. Fast radio bursts.
Let me just check if it's FRBs are fast
radio bursts. Fast radio bursts. FRBs.
Yeah, yeah. Uh so what is the LWA data
set? I'm not sure about that.
LWA data set FRBs.
Uh LWA. What's LWA?
Long wavelength array. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Uh low frequency radio telescopes that
provide unique data sets for studying
FRBs. Okay. Uh yeah. Sir, this is not my
my my field. So I am not sure what I can
say to you. You're the expert, sir.
You're the expert. You're doing
interesting work. So you want to find an
FRB that's under 100 MHz
for Okay.
Yeah. I'm not sure if I can give you any
insights whatsoever. Uh this is very
much u applied applied uh
astrophysics.
Yeah, I'm I'm a pure theoretician. So,
yeah, I I don't have any insights to
offer you, sir. Sorry about that.
CS19 Jin says, "Uh, did you hear the
news about India seizing three Iranian
tankers in response to Iran detaining 16
sailors? What do you make of this?"
Something isn't right, obviously.
So, did Iran detain 16 t 16 sailors?
Why would they do that?
I mean India and Iran have a reasonably
good relationship. So something has gone
wrong clearly. Looks like Iran sees
India as perhaps being on the side of
the US.
Maybe that's how Iran sees us sees India
today. So the question is if they see
India as being on the American side, why
do they see it that way?
Yeah. So looks like things are changing.
Looks like India is being uh armed
twisted by the US.
into picking a side. I remember I had
this live stream in 2024 after Trump won
in which I said that that Trump will ask
India to pick a side. He will say you
can either be with the US or you can be
against the US. There is no such thing
as strategic economy. You have to pick a
side. And when that pressure comes on
India, I said India will have to pick a
side and that side will be Trump. It
will be US. So has it happened? I mean
that is called isn't it? That's called
being wasal. Has that happened?
Does Iran feel that this has happened?
So the indications we are seeing right
now is that India is inching towards the
US. That's the indications that we see.
Whether it is India seizing three
Iranian tankers, whether it is the all
the all the buzz around the AI summit,
whether it is India almost stopping or
possibly entirely stopping purchasing
Russian oil, whether it is other things,
whether it is the American ambassador
and ad navy admiral visiting the army,
Indian army's western command, all these
things if you put together, they seem to
kind of indicate that India is going
towards the US side, which is extremely
concerning, which actually will prove me
to be correct that I I've been saying
for the past few weeks there's a very
high likelihood there's a high
likelihood that India becomes a US vasal
within the next 5 years are we already
on the on the road to that still too
early to say but looks like there are
indications
dial with prios says thoughts on recent
banan protest by INC in AI summit
Look, this is a political matter. So I
typically don't comment about this. I
would say that see this the AI summit
was a global international summit. Uh
and uh when it comes to these things,
you have to keep domestic politics out
of it because it will otherwise affect
India's image. So I would say whatever
happened was unfortunate. Unfortunate.
Fields strong man says you haven't
opened Google maps today. Can you open
and giving give us a mini interesting
historical episode about the Serbian
Bosnia region? Serbian Bosnia region.
Well, I haven't opened maps today.
That's interesting.
Um, okay, let's open maps.
So, uh, Serbian Bosnia region. You see
this entire region that we have,
Slovenia, Croatia, Bosnia, Hatsugina,
Serbia, Montenegro, Kosovo, North
Macedonia, etc.
All of that used to be one country which
is Yugoslavia. And Yugoslavia was broken
up. It was destroyed in um the 1990s
essentially by the Americans
um after the disintegration of the USSR.
The American
rationale was that this was was a nation
that was part which was a satellite
state of the USSR. It was part of the
wars of pact and now that we are the
only superpower left in the world we're
going to do what we want and we will do
we will we will disintegrate the USSR we
will disintegrate Yugoslavia. So
Yugoslavia was broken up and then you
had a civil war in the region, you know,
Bosnians versus Serbs and there was the
issue of Kosovo.
Um the siege of Sarvo
where is Novisad. I mean we had
Yeah, it was pretty pretty nasty stuff
that happened over here. Pretty nasty
stuff.
Yeah. So that's that's the Balkans
region. Obviously you had the Balkan
wars that were the prelude to the first
world war which also went down in this
region. And all the problems you face in
the Balk that the people of the Balkans
face they the root the root cause the
root causes lie in the Ottoman
occupation of the region.
So that's the root cause of all the
problems you face in the Balkan. The
people of the Balkans face the Ottoman
occupation of the region. Ottoman Turks.
The Turks are the root cause. So
hopefully that's a small little
historical episode.
Beckenbau says recently I read about the
Indian mathematician Madhav of Samam
sung
who lived in the 14th century. Many of
his works are renamed by Europeans have
checked his works. Yes, many the Madava
libnitz series. Why does Libnit have to
figure in this? It should be the Madhava
series, right? But they call it the
Madhava Libnit series. Let me show you.
Oh, give me a second.
Okay, so
Madava series
Madava series,
the Taylor series and so on.
Okay, so it's called the Madhava series
here on Wikipedia, but there's something
called the Madhava Limnitz series as
well.
Let's see. Madhava Libnitz series.
What is this now?
Um
okay so it's called by multiple names
so who was Madhava of Sungam
um Madav of SAM Graham.
Yeah. So this is the guy who essentially
came up with calculus
infinite series and and essentially the
precursors of calculus but a lot of the
credit is now taken taken over by the
Europeans.
So u I would I would highly I would I
would invite everybody to look up Madav
of Sangam Graham. One of the great
mathematicians perhaps one of the
greatest mathematicians of of the Kerala
school of mathematics.
Um
look up his life look up look up his
work. Very interesting.
Pratam Bedkar says in Guadalajara,
Mexico was supposed to host the FIFA
World Cup before the CJNG started the
violence. Who are CJNG? Do they have
operations in India also at one point?
Really? I don't know about the CJNG.
Let's find out.
Guadalahara CJNG.
Let's see what is CJ. The Kalisco New
Generation Cartel. Okay.
CJNG.
That's the Khalisco cartel. Is it? Uh,
that's a Mexican criminal syndicate.
Kalisco New Generation Cartel.
Uh, did they have operations in India? I
wasn't aware of this.
Did they have operations in India?
CJNG involvement in India has been found
in association with the meth lab. Well,
well,
in greater Nida. Well, well, okay. So, I
was not aware of this. Um, I am not
aware of the history of this Halisco
cartel. I knew about uh Pablo Escobar.
I knew about Carlos Leather. So, that's
back in the 20th century. I don't know
about the the the newer cartels and the
newer leaders of these cartels and so
on. So uh I'm sure Gualara can still
host matches of the FIFA World Cup as
long as the government of Mexico is able
to bring this violence back under
control. Yeah.
Angad Gallal says do you think there's
water on Titan Saturn and where did you
graduate from the physics and why are
there no laws favoring men seem unfair?
How many questions in one place? Look,
Titan is there water water in Titan. I
think Titan is so Titan is this moon of
Saturn, isn't it? Titan is a moon of
Saturn.
It's larger than our moon and it has a
very thick atmosphere that's a haze of
hydrocarbons
and it's a very very very cold place but
it has lakes and possibly even rivers.
lakes and rivers made of hydrocarbons
like methane.
So that's like minus 200 or something
degrees CCelsius or something like that.
What's the average temperature on Titan?
Around -200°C.
What's the average temperature on Titan,
the moon of Saturn?
Um,
okay. Minus 179° C, right? So obviously
even if there's water there, it's going
to be frozen solid, right? It's going to
be ice. So as far as ice, as as I know,
it's it's mostly uh
uh it's mostly hydrocarbons
on on Titan. Let's still ask the EI. Is
there any water on Titan, the moon of
Saturn?
Let's see. I suppose there must be some
water. Yeah, there's a significant
amount of water, but it's going to be
Yeah, it's going to be So, yeah, the
surface lakes and rivers are made of
liquid ethane, methane, and ethane. The
bedrock is composed of hard frozen
water, ice, and there could be a deep
ocean of liquid water
potentially mixed with ammonia. Okay,
it's believed, but we don't know for
sure if there is there.
Yeah, so that's the deal. But Titan.
Um,
yeah. So, it looks like there's water in
Titan, but it'll be it'll be frozen
solid. Uh, where did I graduate? In
theoretical physics. I graduated in
nuclear physics from the University of
Mumbai. Uh, why are there no laws
favoring men?
That's another of the issues that we
have in India. you know see you know
laws should be impartial laws should be
gender agnostic genderneutral but in
India we have all this stuff right
so obviously laws should be completely
gender agnostic or genderneutral they
can't favor one gender over another but
India is a fantastic country where
everything is skewed so that's what we
have
gora TV says if nations like the US and
China represent the peak of power and
success. Why do their societies appear
increasingly stressed and unhappy?
If this is the end result of reaching
the top, then what are we ultimately
moving toward? That's a very good
question.
Um, if you look at the average
population of China and the average
population of the US, I would say there
is more strife today, at least from what
we see in the US compared to in China.
Um things are really cheap in China.
Food is really cheap in China. In in the
US it's very expensive. So the
government of China has essentially
given the Chinese citizens a better
social contract than what you have in
the US with its uh out and out
capitalism.
Um now the US represents the peak of
power and success. Not China. The US
does represent the peak of power and
success. for its success as a nation.
Individuals in the nation may not be as
successful. There's a tremendous amount
of inequality in the US. Tremendous
inequality.
So that's not the US may be the most
powerful nation in the world, the most
successful nation in the world, but from
a societal perspective, it's not that
successful. There is tremendous
inequality in the US. some people I mean
it's it's a great country to live in if
you are rich if you are wealthy if you
have an income of over $100,000 a year
even that's less actually if if you have
essentially if you're a millionaire with
a net net worth of at least $510 million
then it's a great place to live in
um otherwise I mean at the other end of
the spectrum you have people who work
three jobs just to put food on the table
for their families
so um that's not success. A truly
successful nation would be not just
powerful but its people will also have a
great living standards and they'll also
be very happy. That's not the US. That
is not the US. That's the kind of uh
societal structure the Anglo-Saxon world
has.
China is different and so on. So what so
is this the end result of reaching the
top? There are other ways of reaching
the top also that we don't have examples
of today. Right?
So in the past India was the most
industrialized society in the world.
Let's say during the so-called Harapan
period of our history 3000 BC at that
time the so-called mature Harapan phase
India was the most industrially
industrialized industrially and
technologically advanced civilization on
the planet
and the biggest economy on the planet
and the biggest population group on the
planet
and I'm sure people in India at the time
where there we didn't have that sort of
inequality people would have been way
happier
back then. So there are different models
of success and power and you don't
necessarily need to uh
pray on your own population to make this
happen.
Okay. Gora TV says in a hypothetical
scenario if the Lotus Party were to
scrap the constitution tomorrow and
establish an authoritarian one party
system in India what would be the likely
domest domestic and global reactions?
First of all, the Lotus Party will never
do that. But let's say hypothetically,
so it it does it. What will be the
domestic reactions? Domestically, the
reactions will be split. A large number
of people will actually welcome this
and a certain number of people will
violently oppose this possibly.
So that will be the possible response or
reaction in India.
I would say it's going to be a mixed
reaction in India domestically. I would
say not a large number but a sizable
number of Indians will welcome this.
A sizable number of Indians will be
alarmed
despite not being secular. There's a no
no democracy is great and a sizable
number of people will possibly violently
oppose this sort of thing.
Um
but you can't establish an authoritarian
one party system in a country by simply
issuing a proclamation. You have to be
able to enforce it and enforcing is a
whole different story and that's why it
doesn't happen in India. Um what will
the will be the likely global reactions?
All negative all negative from every
side
because that actually can make India
strong right that's why everyone will
will have a negative reaction whether
it's the US the UK the European nations
whether it's China whether it is uh
Pakistan
most of these reactions will be pretty
negative Russia may not have a negative
reaction to this surprisingly
um
Turkey will be very negative to to to
this most European nations will have a
negative reaction
China will have a ne negative reaction.
Russia may not. Several African nations
may not and so on. But the nations that
matter will have a negative reaction to
this.
Fields strong man says if you were to
swap two countries present countries but
old empires geographically then which
were to swap would
um if you were to swap two countries
present countries but old empires
geographically then which were to swap
would have had the most impact in
changing world history local
internationally. I have no idea what
you're saying sir.
If I were to swap two countries
geographically,
then which two swap would have the most
impact
on changing world history locally and
geographically, internationally?
I don't know.
Um,
I haven't thought about it.
If you place any of the old
civilizations in North America,
the way the Anglo-Saxons have taken
over, that would obviously change world
history in a variety of ways and so on.
Yeah, but I haven't thought about it.
So, so can't say really can't say. Abida
Singh says, "Can't we use the surface
area of naval ships and install solar
panels there on the sides? Maybe will it
be too insignificant to make any change?
This the the
naval ships they need to be made of a
certain kind of material, pretty strong
material
and you can't simply attach solar panels
to the sides. It's a pretty interesting
idea. It's a good thought experiment
but I'm sure this must have been thought
of and obviously it would not have
worked
because if you have n solar panels on
the sides that at any given time half at
least half the solar panels are not
being being used
and uh solar panels don't really
generate that much electricity comp
compared to what a naval ship needs a
military ship needs A military ship
doesn't care about pollution or
whatever. A military ship cares about
power.
You will never find solar panels on
military ships. They will use the
dirtiest possible technologies if
required to gain maximum power output
from their engine. So you can have these
things, these experiments on cruise
vessels and and civilian ships. On
military ships, there's no
experimentation of this kind done. Never
ever. You want the most efficient and
maximum possible power output from your
engines and your engine gives you the
electricity you need and every single
solar solar panel you add to a ship
increases the weight of the ship. Why do
that? So you won't do these experiments
on military vessels.
Uh Mashov says how to stop
overoptimizing when planning study.
Well, I am overoptimizing
Um
how do you stop over it's called
analysis paralysis right? You keep on
analyzing, you keep on studying. I mean
not studying, you keep on planning and
making small changes, small tweaks. Uh
I would say stick to what works. When it
comes to the education system of India,
it's an ancient education system.
Nothing ancient as in like 100 200
years. You know exactly what succeeds,
right? Exactly what what gives you
success. study so many so many hours a
day um while far from the exam once the
exam exam is approaching solve question
papers and so on. So stick to the
routine stick to the stick to what works
and that way you stop over optimizing I
suppose.
Ang Gal says where do you did you
graduate? I already answered this
question. Uh what do you think is the
future of NATO and UNO United Nations
Organization and do you think Jews are
playing Dice in Trump's decisions?
Um
what do I think is the future of NATO?
NATO will be allowed to exist as long as
it is useful to the United States. So I
think NATO will most likely continue to
exist
uh for the foreseeable future next 10 20
years. That's what I think will happen.
it will certainly still be valuable and
and useful to the United States. So
yeah, now
you know United Nations the United
Nations is useless. It's it's it's of no
use anymore to anybody. I mean not to
anybody but to most of us it's of no
use. It is obsolete. But as long as it
serves some purpose for nations like the
US or China, it will be allowed to
continue existing.
And there are some nations that see some
kind of benefit from having these
ceremonial organizations.
So yeah, it may be allowed to continue
existing but really it needs to be
reformed or dismantled. But right now it
will continue. So as long as the US is
the most powerful nation in the world
and as long as the US sees some value in
the UN,
as long as that happens, it will allow
it will be allowed to continue existing.
Do I think Jews are playing dice in
Trump's decisions? I have no idea.
Karthik Ayar says Elon Musk is a liar.
He has been lying about Mars and Tesla
for the past Tesla FSD for the past 10
years. He says he will focus on the moon
first. FSD means this the self-driving
system has more crashes.
Um so we have to understand that Elon
Musk is not an inventor. He's a
businessman.
Tesla wasn't founded by Elon Musk. Tesla
was founded by two other gentlemen and
then Elon Musk took over the company. He
acquired the company.
He did found SpaceX but he is not the
chief engine. I mean he may have the
title of chief engineer, chief
everything but the actual work is done
by other people by other people. So uh
Elon Musk is a great businessman. He's
not some great scientist or engineer or
whatever. Okay. Now u he has been saying
for the longest time that he that
humanity must reach Mars. Humanity must
become interplanetary and now he has
pivoted in the past couple of maybe past
one month or so and he he now says that
they will now SpaceX will now focus on
the moon and we will not focus on
reaching Mars first. We'll first focus
on reaching the moon which is
essentially a U-turn.
Right? So if you consider that to be an
example of Elon Musk lying, well then I
suppose it is lying. Maybe it's just a
strategic U-turn. But why didn't they
think of think of this earlier? Clearly
reaching the moon is easier. You can you
have multiple launch windows in a month.
If you want to reach Mars, you have a
once in 26 months launch window. So
obviously reaching the moon is way
easier. It makes more sense to reach the
moon first. But he has been hyping up
Mars, Mars, Mars, Mars for years and now
suddenly it's the moon. Uh yeah. So
that's that's true. Uh the FSD. What is
Tesla? What is the full form of FSD? Let
me see.
Tesla FSD.
What is FSD?
Uh full self-driving. The self-driving
system, right? Uh does it have a lot of
crashes? I have not been keeping track
of it, so I don't know. I've heard of
crashes here and there once in a while,
but I haven't been keeping track of how
many crashes have happened.
Uh so yeah, he has been saying I don't
know for close to a decade that next
year we're going to have full
self-driving. Next year we're going to
have full st self driving and we still
don't have full selfdriving.
Since when has he been claiming? Let's
see.
Since when has Elon Musk been claiming
that full self-driving is just a year
away?
Yeah, exactly. So, Elon Musk has been
claiming that Tesla's full self-driving
capability is roughly one or two years
away or feature complete by year end
consistently since at least 2014 2015.
And uh yeah, there we have it. Even
today, more than a decade since he
started making the claims, it is still
not a fully self-driving system. So, is
does it mean that he's a liar or does it
mean that he's over optimistic or does
is he overpromising? What's the deal?
Well, I suppose I suppose you can make
your own decision based on what we know.
Okay. Karthik says NEA has advised
Indians to leave Iran. Let's find out,
shall we? Let's find out.
Has the Indian MEA advised Indians to
leave Iran?
What happened? Let's try again. Has the
Indian MEA advised Indians to leave
Iran?
India issues safety alert, urges
citizens to leave Iran by all means
possible, etc. 5 hours ago, 7 hours ago,
9 hours ago and so on. Yeah, it looks
like this has actually indeed happened.
Looks like uh stuff is going to hit the
fan soon. Looks like that. Very
unfortunate. Um
it will be unfortunate for Iran if the
Americans affect the regime change.
Um but looks like it's almost inevitable
like I explained a couple of hours
earlier in this very live stream.
Abishek Singh says can we make a move on
P if China moves on Taiwan.
See P
is under occupation like it like it says
by Pakistan. But who is Pakistan's
protector? It's the United States. The
United States does not want India to be
able to take the the region of PK.
So even if China makes a move on Taiwan,
it will be difficult for us to make I
mean we could make a move on the on P.
We could even take it over possibly.
Yeah. But the Americans will will impose
a lot of pain on us for that for that.
So we can make a move but will the
government of India have the
the fortitude to make that move is the
question. We can we could make a move.
Obviously the consequences will be will
not be very very pretty. the Americans
will take a variety of actions against
us. But we can even make a move on Puk
now and we can still definitely take it
over. We have the military power to do
that. But we aren't doing that, right?
So
Kanesh Koshik says, "Thank you, sir, for
your consistent and precious insights."
33. Thank you so much, sir. Thank you so
much. Thank you. Kanesk
Palak thing says is chemtrails real at
18 it terrifies me. So I don't know I
mean see since I was a little kid I've
been seeing these contrails in the sky
left behind by jet planes. Now these
contrails that you see in the sky are
typically water vapor that is released
as part of the exhaust of a jet engine.
What's a jet engine? It's the your turbo
fine or whatever right in your Boeing
and Airbus and other aircraft and the
fuel is kerosene
which is a hydrocarbon fuel and it's
burnt it's combusted right and one of
the byproducts of this combustion is is
H2 or water vapor and that's what forms
the majority of these contrails that we
see as these yeah the aircraft
contrails. So, I've been seeing that
since I was a little kid. But there is
this theory that it's actually
chemical trails, chemtrails. And uh the
theory is that allegedly some
governments are are are are spraying
certain chemicals in the atmosphere with
the objective of making certain changes.
Maybe I don't know what what the
objectives are. Is it real? Well,
it could be real. I don't have any
evidence that it's real. I don't have
any evidence that it's false. So I can't
say theoretically it's possible. But is
it truly the case that this has been
going on? I don't know about that. So
this is called a conspiracy theory. This
is categorized by most people is a
conspiracy theory. If you go go to
Wikipedia, it'll say it's a conspiracy
theory. I'm sure. But um it's possible,
but I don't know if it's true or not.
Sharma says the west that values
independence, freedom and people that
mind and people mind their own business
is better to collectivist Indian Chinese
societies that are obedient.
Well then that's one perspective of
that's one way of looking at the world.
It depends on you what you value. If you
are a person who values freedom,
independence,
then the west, the United States is a
great place for you. the place where you
can drive endlessly for hours
on the open highways,
right? You can drive for hours with
nobody bothering you
on the American highways. There's
complete freedom in the US as an
individual. So if you're that sort of
person who who values that who desires
that then the US is for you, not the
West. You go to Europe, you won't find
that. The Europe is a very nosy pokey
society. Okay? I mean, not all of
Europe, but Europe is different from the
US.
You won't find the same independence and
freedom in Europe, by the way, that you
find in the United States.
People won't mind their business that
much in Europe. In the US, yes, they
will. And also depends on which part of
the US you're in. So, it's up to you. If
you are a person who who craves this
freedom, who craves independence, then
the US is the right place for you. I'm
not sure if even the US may be changing
a bit right now. Yeah. Yeah. It's
entirely up to you, sir. You do you.
Don't let anyone tell you what to do.
Excuse me.
Abishek says Afghanistan vowed to avenge
Pakistan and give tears of blood. So,
the Pakistanis launched air strikes on
Afghanistan recently, like a day or two
ago. Apparently, it's killed a whole
bunch of Afghan civilians. The
Pakistanis keep doing that. The Afghans
will take some action against Pakistan
and the Pakistanis will deserve every
bit of it. I would say
NPS says
in my opinion the great filter, one of
the great filters is efficient human
time scale interstellar travels
technology.
If humans can't leave the solar system,
they can't survive as a species for a
very long time. What's my point of view?
So when it comes to uh
when it comes to the firmy paradox, the
fmy paradox is can be expressed in in
the form of a question
where is everyone in what's the context?
If the universe is full of alien life or
or is if the universe is full of life
everywhere then where is everyone? Why
don't we see anybody? Why don't we see
any evidence of life on other star
systems? Right? Where is everybody? And
one of the answers that could perhaps
resolve this paradox is perhaps there
are there is something called the great
filters
that ensure that you know no
civilization becomes so advanced that it
can start traveling
across inter interstellar distances. One
of the great filters could be nuclear
war that every civilization eventually
discovers every alien species eventually
discovers nuclear weapons and leads to
nuclear war and then that's why they can
never go beyond that. That's one example
of a great filter. So uh NPS is saying
one of the great filters in his or her
opinion is efficient human time scale
interstellar troubles technology.
If humans can't leave solar system they
can't survive as a species for a very
long time.
Um it's not just about humans. It's
about any species about any intelligent
species. Maybe on Sabadan, maybe Taoai,
maybe maybe uh Proxima Centtory, maybe
some stars from the Andromeda in
Andromeda galaxy, whatever. It's not
just about humans. So it it's possible.
But see the thing is there are so many
different ways of traveling in space
that we know of theoretically at least.
Basard Ramjuts Ramjuts for example,
that's
that works according to physics. It's
very farfetched but it can work if you
can make it happen. Um antimatter
propulsion that's also possible. I mean
theoretically at least if you can
harness sufficient antimatter. So
there's lot of ways of traveling across
interstellar spaces. We don't have it
right now because we are primitive but
we can conceive of the physics behind
these technologies.
So I'm not sure if if it's one of the
viable great filters. I think nuclear
war is a viable great filter and some
other things as well. Okay. Godliness
says does the cosmological timeline big
bang to heat death conflict with the
human experience of time as a continuous
non-physical present? Even physics
fails to understand conscious
experience. Why? Why does physics fail
to understand or describe conscious
experience? It's not that physics fails.
It's that our understanding of physics
fails.
Our understanding of physics has
limitations.
And our limitations prevent our physics
models from being able to explain or
describe or even define consciousness.
That is the issue. My dear friends,
our models of physics are limited. They
are limited by the limitations of our
brain.
What's the most intelligent a person can
be? I mean a intelligent person is 120
IQ, right? A genius person is 150 IQ.
An alien level intelligence person is
one maybe 200 IQ or something. But what
if you need an IQ of 500 on this scale
to actually be able to develop a physics
model that can actually describe,
define, and explain consciousness. So
it's not a problem with physics. It's a
problem with our intellect.
We are a primitive species. We aren't
advanced enough to be able to do these
things. Right now does the cosmological
timeline big bang to heat death heat
death conflict with the human experience
of time as a continuous non-physical
present. See this cosmological timeline
big bang to heat death it's theoretical.
We don't know for sure if it is the
right timeline.
We don't know what the universe is going
to experience in the future.
Heat death is one possible future but
we're not sure 100% that it will it will
happen.
We don't know what kind of universe we
inhabit. Uh we don't know whether it it
is a cyclical universe you know with
with a big bang and expansion and a
contraction in a big crunch. That's a
cyclical universe. Then there is
conformal cyc cyclical cosmology. the
eons you know idea of Roger Penrose
which makes seems to make a lot of
sense. Um so that's a kind of cyclical
version of the universe but a different
kind of cyclical version. Then you have
the heat death you the big crunch sorry
the the big rip and so on big rip etc.
These are different models of what could
happen in the future. We don't know
which which one is correct. We don't
know. Uh our experience
of time is constrained by so many things
including the fact that we inhabit
physical bodies
and a lot of what we experience is is
because of the the these flesh and blood
bodies we inhabit. So um and the the
cosmological timeline from big bang to
heat death is one of the possible
scenarios that we have been able to
conceive and think of based on our very
primitive and rudimentary understanding
of the universe.
Debojit says like George RR Martin's
layered tales echo real history. What if
our epics too were rich fictions
inspired by true events? What are my
thoughts? My thoughts, my belief, my the
way I see it, our epics were actual
historical events. That's how I see it.
That's how I see it.
Shu Zero says, "Do Indian government not
care about anti-India cyber war and SCO
up all over social media. It's so
exhausting and disheartening being
Indian on net. The anti-India content
factory is self perpetuating and having
real life consequences. But the
government of India doesn't care to uh
do anything to combat that." Well, I
have never understood the government of
India's approach and attitude towards
this. If other countries look Pakistan
and China use these big bot farms and
whatnot to and even the west, even the
western countries, they use all these
underhand means to amplify this this
anti-India hatred and these narratives.
Why doesn't the government of India
which also has access to social media
platforms not use the same techniques
and methods and and means? We just
don't. We simply don't.
And why don't we use propaganda? Every
nation has their own propaganda outlet.
BBC, CNN, uh, Dutch, well, uh, C, CCTN,
every country has a propaganda outlet,
multiple propaganda outlets. India has
nothing. I just don't understand why the
government of India simply doesn't play
this game. I don't understand it. It
simply
makes no sense to me.
So I don't have an answer to your
question and I I share your frustration.
Vir Kamut says isn't it abhorrent and
disgusting that we've continued to play
Pakistan?
Imagine if Arab nations played with
Israel. Why do Hindus have so little
self-respect when they see no issue? See
it's not about Hindus having no
self-respect. It's about the government
of India being a secular government.
They genuinely see themselves as
secular. that genuinely believe in
secularism.
Now I have been saying this for a long
time. India should not just boycott
Pakistan. India should ensure Pakistan
can't play international cricket. India
is the most powerful cricket playing
nation, the biggest cricket economy. The
BCCI is the richest board.
If the BCCI pulls out of international
cricket, then all the other boards will
suffer financially terribly.
So if we insist that nobody plays
Pakistan, if you play Pakistan, we will
not play you. If we insist on this,
everyone will stop playing Pakistan.
But we are not doing that. Now, who
controls the BCCI?
So why does India not push Pakistan out
of international cricket? Why doesn't
India do it? A terrorist nation, an evil
terrorist nation. Why doesn't India
allow push them out? I suppose India
doesn't want to for some reason.
Is this something to do with lack of
self-respect?
Don't don't blame Hindus for not having
self-respect. Blame the government of
India. Those people,
do they really represent the the the
ordinary Hindus of India today? I'm not
sure. So yeah, once again, I don't have
an answer why the government of India
still allows these cricket matches to
proceed with Pakistan.
Juggernaut says, "Give me top two book
recommendations on world history." Look,
world history is a massive subject. If
there is one book that teaches world
history, it can't cover everything. It
will not even cover 10%. It'll give you
very high level overviews of whatever.
And world history is so vast, so deep,
so broad. There's the first world war,
the second world war. That's only the
past 100 or so years, right? There's
19th century history, 18th century
history. this history of all these
different civilizations. You can't give
two book recommendations, my friend. How
can you do that? I don't know. Um,
I have a bunch of books here. I'm
looking at them.
I don't know. Book recommendations about
world history. Two. You just want two.
How does it work? Doesn't work like
that. Doesn't work like that.
And I don't know of any any one book
that teaches that that covers the whole
of world history. I think there's a book
by Mark Twain or HG Wells. I'm not sure.
Let's see.
By the way, I'm not recommending this.
I'm trying to find out.
Mark Twain World History.
Did he have a book on history?
Uh, no. Or was it HG Wells?
Let's see.
HG Wells, World History.
Did he have a book? Yeah. Yeah. He had a
book called A Short History of the
World. Well, I haven't read this. I've
I've heard of it. So, I don't know if
you want books and book recommendations
on world history. I'm not the guy for
that. I I
don't know of any one book or two books
that teach the whole of world history.
Cosmic Cab says, "I'm an architect in
Rome. You inspired me to start a channel
on funny satire history, science, and
politics. I'd be grateful if you check
it and share feedback." Okay, I shall
check it out and maybe I can comment on
your channel in that case. Uh, so I'll
not do the do a search right now because
it'll Yeah, but yeah, I will check it
out. Cosmic Cab. Uh in case I forget,
let me do it right away because yeah,
once the live stream is done, I may not
be inclined to do that. Let me see. So
it's what? Cosmic cab. Let me see.
Cosmic
cab.
Okay. This is the one.
Okay. Interesting. Interesting.
Interesting.
Uh who has the cards? New year.
Okay. Interesting. I'll keep this open.
I I'll check it out later. All right.
Sure. And uh yeah, sounds interesting.
Let other people also subscribe.
Subscribe. Sure. Okay.
NPS says, "Can an individual make a
career in astrophysics if the person is
weak in mathematics?" Uh typically no.
Typically, look in any field of physics,
you need to be competent in mathematics.
Yeah. See, when it comes to
astrophysics, you're going to need
things. You're going to have to be
wellversed in quantum mechanics, fluid
dynamics,
uh thermodynamics,
and so many other things. For that, you
need mathematics. You need a certain
level of mathematics. So you can't
really make a career in any discipline,
any branch of physics if you are weak in
mathematics. You have you will have to
address that deficiency. And it's not
like mathematics is some unnatural
thing. If you are not good in
mathematics, if you're weak in
mathematics, it means at some level see
mathematics is like a building. There
are different floors. Some of the floors
are weak. Go and address those def
deficiencies and your foundations will
get stronger. That's how we do it. All
right sir. All the best. Adimish Bharti
has gifted 10 memberships of the
channel. Thank you so much sir. That's
very kind of you. Thank you so much.
Swastik says Chanaka would definitely
approve of Yog Giji today. All right
sir. Okay.
Gora TV says is there a connection
between the audience described in our
Sanskrit literature Aryat in the
Mahabharat and the arian of the
so-called crappy Arian invasion theory
in our Sanskrit literature.
There is no
description of Arians
as an ethnic group. There is no
depiction of arians. There is no
reference to any ethnic group called
arians.
The the word the term arrya you'll find
it everywhere in Sanskrit literature.
Okay.
And Arya in Sanskrit means a noble
person, a person of good behavior and
good uh refined good behavior.
That's Arya. It means a noble person, a
civilized person. That's what Arya
means. It's not an ethnic term. Our
Persian cousins,
they used Arya as a ethnic term.
Okay.
Of course we have this term called Arya
which means the land of the Arya people
because we are civilized that way but
that kind of you could say has some kind
of ethnic connotations but that would
mean that the whole of the subcontinent
is Arya people.
Now this so-called Arian invasion theory
which is now migration theory etc that
says that people from central Asia and
Europe white-kinned people came and
invaded or migrated to India and they
were the ethnic arians which is there is
no connection whatsoever with the area
people described in our literature
there's no connection whatsoever
says the genetic article traces of
middle eastern lineages in Indian
Muslims says India Iranian Shia have 80%
recent Iranian ancestry cluster with uh
Europeans and Middle Easterners distinct
distant from non-Muslims. What does it
mean genetically?
Traces of Middle Eastern lineages in
Indian Muslims.
So u it says Iranian Shia have 80%
recent Iranian ancestry.
They cluster with Europeans and Middle
Easterners distant from non-Muslims.
What does it mean genetically? I'm not
sure what we mean what they mean by
recent
um Iranian ancestry.
What does Okay, let's see. I'm not sure.
Okay, let me see. Let me let me try and
find out. What does the term recent
Iranian ancestry mean genetically?
Recent Iranian ancestry. Oh, 10,000.
That's not recent. Come on. That's the
Neolithic farmers and what what not. Um
okay, I'll have to look at the paper.
Without looking at the paper, I cannot
tell you something that may not be
correct. I have to look at the paper
because in each paper there's a specific
context.
Recent Iranian my ancestry
and they cluster with Europeans and
Middle Easterners distant from
non-Muslims. Genetically, it means
they're part of a population group which
has affinity, genetic genetic affinity
with Europeans and Middle Easterners.
That's what it seems to say. But I'll
have to read the paper to give you a a
proper interpretation of what it really
means. But it looks like genetically
they're closer to Europeans and Middle
Easterners. That's what it looks like.
Yashwan Sudir says, "Thoughts on Indian
tourists to Jiju Island being detained?"
Well, thoughts,
you have to be careful with your travel.
Don't blame,
be prepared for all pro problems, all
possibilities when you travel. Don't
blame the host nation. No, look, it's
possible it was because of racism, but
be aware of the fact that certain
countries have racism
and be prepared for that. Don't make
assumptions that for example so and so
island visa fee travel is is allowed.
Don't assume it means all all people. I
mean, I would say the blame is 50% the
the Korean government, 50% the Indian
travelers
because these problems seem to happen in
Korea. There seems to be anti-Indian
racism in Korea.
So, it's it's a known fact, right?
So, why can't you be better prepared?
So, yeah, I would say you have to be
careful when in trouble. Pratip Kumar
Roy says about Bohemian Grove. What
about Bohemian Grove? What's the
question?
What are my What's my opinion about
that? I've heard of it as some kind of
satanic ritual ceremony happens there.
Apparently, the the evil pedo elite of
the US participates in it. Apparently,
allegedly
connections with with Epstein. I'm not
sure about that, but yeah, that's what
I've heard. I haven't studied the
history of the Bohemian Grove and all
that in detail, so I can't really say,
but I've heard the connections with the
evil satanic American elite.
Hanish says, "How do you remember so
many things and their correct name and
everything? I can't even remember what I
had for breakfast yesterday." I don't
know. Everyone's different. Some people
remember stuff, some people don't. I
forget more things than I remember,
actually. Can I remember what I had for
breakfast yesterday?
um possibly but probably 3 4 days before
a go what I have for breakfast if you
ask me I may not remember so um
yeah it depends everyone's different I
kind of remember some some things at
least some things
kit Gupta says good evening sir can you
please help me understand the cause of a
conflict that is for that I love to
bring in an expert I it's part of the of
the of the Balkcon conflict of the 1990s
for sure. It has something to do with
the religion. Two Abrahamic religions in
the region. One is Christianity, one is
Islam. The root causes are the Ottoman
occupation of the region. Uh the
Americans definitely played a big role
in this. But what were the specific
details etc. I am not very clear about
right now. Okay. So if you want to
understand this, I will have to bring in
an expert. maybe resume my podcast for a
bit. I can think of the right expert for
that actually. But yeah, so don't
remember the specific details right now.
Hanishama says this might sound stupid
but why do Indian windows have grills in
them and in western houses it's mostly
open glass? Why is that?
Um
see in the west if somebody comes break
your breaks your window and steal
something typically the police will
catch the thief and um and the insurance
will take care of uh whatever you lost.
In India nobody's going to going to
bring you back what you lost. That's why
in India we prefer to have grills in our
windows. At least historically it's been
that way and that's historically been
that way and only after India came under
foreign occupation
right because in India law and order is
it's not very very reliable justice is
also not very reliable uh insurance is
also not not very reliable so you want
to make sure that you are safe
as a teenager starting his career hookup
culture is very tempting from inside I
know it's wrong and animalike and I'm
able to keep distance until now but I
need solid reason to keep it that way.
Solid reasons to not participate in
hookup culture.
I don't know about solid reasons for me
it's it's never something that appealed
to me.
It's not part of our culture
of our ancestral original Indian
culture. Today anything is anything is
fine. Uh it's very tempting. Yeah. rack
up your body count or whatever they you
call it. But what do you get out of it?
What
what do you I don't know. Um I don't
know if I can give you a
clear solid reason to not be involved in
hookup culture.
Um,
a connection between two human beings
has to be meaningful and substantial,
right?
Not just like transactional and
animallike.
Hookup culture is is is transactional,
right? Isn't it? It's very
transactional.
It it I suppose if you participate if if
I were to do that, it will leave me
disgusted with humanity eventually.
shallow, meaningless, transactional
approach. I I I don't know. I'm not sure
if I can inunciate and explain and
articulate exactly
why I dislike it. From my perspective,
I'm very clear. First of all, it's not
part of our culture. Secondly, um I am
it doesn't give me any any there's no no
meaning in it.
Everything you do should have some
meaning.
That's how I see it. Um, I'm sure lots
of people see it differently. So, I
don't know if I can give you solid
reasons, but my advice is don't do that.
Don't get involved in that such things.
Pratip Kumar Royce says, "Do you think
the rich
tech societies,
societies have secret knowledge about
life? Ancient science, geometry,
religion, finance, etc.
secret knowledge about life. No, I don't
think they have any secret knowledge
about life. Ancient science, modern
science is way more advanced than
ancient science.
Geometry,
we do hyper geometry today, right? Um
religion well religion maybe finance
rich these secret societ so societies
are about protecting certain individuals
and protecting certain agendas they
don't have any secret knowledge they may
try and portray like that there they are
really meaningful and all that but it's
all about it's all about u
serving vested interests
that's what secret societies are all
about it's not about it's not that they
have some secret knowledge I don't
imagine that's the case
uh Pratip Kumar Roy says how to do
business in India bribe politicians you
never bribe a politician directly
allegedly
you allegedly only bribe intermediaries
such as bureaucrats and so on allegedly
you don't allegedly directly bribe
politicians
politicians are too careful these days
they have intermediaries to deal with
these
Uh really now Miss Patel says are any of
the nine school Hindu schools of thought
atheistic? Yeah. The Charvak school of
thought is is an atheistic school of
thought. It's it's pure materialism. It
says that everything you see that your
senses can perceive that's the that's
all that exists in in the universe.
There's nothing beyond that. And it says
that the there is no soul, there is no
atma, there is no God, does nothing. And
the only purpose and objective of life
should be to enjoy life and enjoy
material pleasures. That is the Charvaka
school of thought. It is the atheistic
school of thought. That's part of Hindu
dharma.
Okay. Pratipumar Roy says why aren't the
Hindus at least the Brahmans not taught
religion? No Vic studies, no laws of
Manu, nothing. Everything is secularized
help.
Well, the government won't do it. The
government is essentially an anti-Hindu
government. Like I've said in the past,
India, I've been saying this for years
actually that India is the most
hindophobic nation on the planet. India
is a Hindu phobic apathide state. So the
government of India will teach you
nothing whether you're Brahmin or
whether you're whatever.
If you want these traditions to continue
and not die out, you're going to have to
do it yourself privately, individually
or as a family. Everything is is
secularized. Everything is anti-Hindu in
India.
V S says India recently joined the PAX
silica group spearheaded by the US. Do
you think this grouping would be able to
counter success China successfully or
will it end up like Quad or AUK US? It's
structured as I see as far as I see
differently from the Quad or AUK US.
It's about securing supply chains,
reliable supply chains for rare earth
elements and uh yeah rare earths and and
critical critical elements.
Um and India obviously has been invited
to join this. India has joined it
because India is has probably the
world's largest reserves of rare earths
which are completely untapped.
Uh so that's the thing that's why India
has joined. Uh it's not about countering
China. It's about creating
supply chains that are independent of
China. It certainly has all the
potential to be able to become
successful in that in a few years.
Ab says in the last 2 three years
there's been a change to the world
order. Would we would it be fair to say
that Indic religions are the last living
memory of the old world? Yes. Yes.
the Indic religions the the Dharmic
the Dharmic um culture is the last
memories of the old world.
The rigida is the oldest literature
known to humankind and it's it shows you
a glimpse of a very ancient society the
society of our our ancestors. So the
Indian religions the indices are the
last living memory of the old world. No
question about that.
Gor TV says why can't airliners be
equipped with massive emergency
parachutes that could at least reduce
crash damage if not fully prevent it
allowing a safer descent into in case of
total engine failure.
very impractical.
I'll tell you why it's very impractical.
Uh let's say an airliner has 200
passengers, which means you need at
least 200
parachutes plus let's say seven or eight
more for the crew. A parachute, let's
say the whole package, it it
um it it weighs maybe let's say 5 kilos.
Let's say 5 kilos. So you multiply that
by 200 that's a,000 kilos of weight
increase
right
1,000 kilos 1 ton imagine
the the how much more fuel will have to
be spent by the airliner and how how
much the range will be reduced doesn't
make any sense secondly even if you gave
you allow everyone to have a parachute
let's say something goes wrong how do
you have people parachuting out
in military aircraft. Okay,
let's see
military aircraft parachute jump.
So, typically in military aircraft, you
have this massive ramp that opens up.
Can you see this?
And the guys who are jumping out are
very very well trained. You can't have
civilians just jumping out of a aircraft
when there is no such massive ramp ramp
that's available. Right?
See over here this aircraft has this
massive door that opens up and that
that's what allows people to jump off
safely.
If you have in in in commercial
airliners you have doors on the sides.
you try to put a finger out, your whole
hand is going to get get, you know,
knocked back by the speed of the wind.
So, it's almost impossible for someone
to jump out. And then there's the
engines that are that are operational.
They may suck people in. So, it doesn't
make any sense. It just doesn't make any
sense for u you know, civilian airliners
to be equipped with massive emergency
parachutes. Doesn't make It's not It's
not practical. Not practical.
Peacekeeper says a local politician in
Dajuling is a CIA funded and he is
aspire acting as an aspiring Zalinsky
calls himself a social worker and is con
converting people to a foreign religion.
Well,
yeah, it's it's terrible and it's not
surprising.
Dargiling, is it okay? I hope the
government takes cognizance of this. I
doubt if they will for some reason.
Yeah, that's where India is today.
But at least uh thank you for letting us
all know.
Ah Sarkcar says AI jobs are moving to
low code better to be in social in SDE
software de what is SDE?
Um
SDE software development
s what is SDE? Oh software development
engineer better to be ill software
development engineer. AI jobs are moving
to low code.
Uh okay. Okay. I'm not exactly sure what
you're saying but all right sir. Thank
you so much. Pratip Kumar Roy says why
don't we have private military
contractors in India like Blackwater etc
also why aren't we allow allowed to
carry weapons guns etc people of good
repute should be allowed the Indian
government doesn't want to empower the
citizens of India the the entire Indian
state machinery and apparatus is is the
a continuation of the British apparatus
that saw the people as enemies
Right.
And that's why it's we're just
continuing what the British did. That's
why people aren't allowed to carry guns
or or weapons of any kind. I agree that
people of good reput should be allowed
to carry weapons. But no, in India, this
won't happen because we are still a
colonized country. Uh why don't we have
private military operators like
Blackwater in India? I don't know. Maybe
it's a good idea to have private mil,
you know, these paramilitaries that can
take care of Indian interests abroad
wherever we have investments. Why not?
It's a good idea, but perhaps because we
don't have significant massive
investments abroad like the Chinese are,
they have investments and and and
projects going on in almost like half of
the African nations and they do need
security and it's Russian
parliamentaries that typically provide
security at a at a price to the Chinese.
In the case of India, we don't have such
massive projects. We may have a few
handful here and there but nothing
massive, right? That's why we don't have
private military contractors. Maybe
maybe that's the reason why.
Viri
Vinchi WMA says, "Have you heard any
songs of music master Ilia Raja? How do
you like his songs? He's the best and
he's a living legend." I'm sure I must
have heard his songs, but I don't
remember which is which are his songs.
Um,
I've heard that he's an absolute living
legend. I'm sure I've heard his songs
but right now I can't remember which
which songs I've heard that are of that
are his songs. So yeah, he's obviously
very highly respected and regarded as a
living legend. I'm sure with very good
reason. Yeah. Pratip Kumar Roy says one
of my friends Java developer recently
changed his company. Coding
they do that. He has no idea. AI does
everything. Future of software engineers
is doomed.
It's possible. Yeah, it's it's pretty
pretty
clear that most coding
going forward will be done by AI. Now,
AI does write a lot of extraneous code.
It's not very tight code
and uh it's not the kind of tight,
concise, elegant code that a senior
developer would write. AI writes way
more lines of code, but it works. It's
it's going to be hard to maintain by
humans in the future, which means AI
will even do the maintenance. But yes,
AI is is taking taking up all of the
major coding work in the world today.
And uh
possibly the future of software
engineers is doomed. Possibly. I I think
the world will still need software
engineers, but we will not need hundreds
of thousands of software engineers
anymore. Yeah. So, we're going to need
few fewer software engineers and higher
quality software engineers.
GS662 says, "I had commerce plus plus
mathematics in 12th, wanted to shift to
STEM but was denied the exam due to lack
of physics and chemistry. If I prepare
yourself and clear the exam but not
eligible but science students pursuing
law vat without legal degrees in 12th
this is the absurdity of the Indian
education system
this is the absurdity
it's a rotten system it's pure garbage
why can't people be given the option to
change their stream
let them do the preparation
Why not? Why do you force people to
remain at the same stream? Why don't you
give people options? Why don't you give
students options? Why don't you empower
students? Why not?
I just don't get it. The Indian
education system is trash. It's garbage.
So many stories come out. Horror
stories.
Just terrible. Absolutely terrible. I'm
sorry this happened to you, sir.
Anka Kachab says good evening ma'am your
views on the mystery around Mount Kilash
why no expedition team has been able to
achieve the summit many other weird
claims like alteration in the per
perception of time sudden illness men
aging faster etc what could be the
reason so first of all let's address the
question as to why has no team been able
to achieve the summit it's because no
team is allowed to even attempt
climbing the mountain
the Mountain is a holy mountain to three
religions.
Well,
it's technically three now. Hinduism,
Buddhism, and Bourne. Borne is the
original religion of Tibet.
Pre pre-harmic religion. It's also very
polytheistic and also which means it is
entirely compatible with Dharmic
religion. So three religions technically
regard Mount Kalash as a sacred holy
mountain and today Tibet is under the
Chinese occupation but the Chinese
government doesn't allow anybody to
attempt any
climbing expedition on the mountain
because of the holy nature of the
mountain. So that's the first point. Um
what's the mystery around Mount Kash?
There are all kinds of claims that are
made about about Mount Kilash that uh
it's it's a hollow pyramid and there is
some nuclear reactor inside and whatnot.
People say all these things. U I have
seen videos of of weird aerial phenomena
like UFO like phenomena apparently
around the mountain, you know, blurry
videos of of that. So what is the deal
there? Is it is it like someone I've
seen people flying drones and and drone
footage from the top of Kaash Mountain.
So people do fly drones there. that
could perhaps explain some of these um
weird aerial phenomena. It's possible.
Uh some people claim there's there are
alterations in perception of time and
people age faster or slower. Some people
face face illnesses. I have no idea.
I haven't visited Bash so I can't say it
anything from my own experience. Uh
people make all kinds of claims. People
like to imagine that something
fascinating, something something unusual
happened to you when you visited the
holy mountain. Um, of course it's a
place where where Indians, Hindus and
Buddhists and everybody else has been
visiting for thousands of years. You
have sadus who do sadna over there and
there is this reputation the mountain
has obviously it's the abboard of Lord
Shiva. It's a holy mountain and it's a
place of supernatural events.
So yeah, that's why there are all these
stories that are associated with the
mountain. What's my view on this? My
view is that I have no idea.
I have no idea.
I don't know what could be the reason. I
have no idea. I can't give you any
scientific explanation for all these
claims. I don't even know if the claims
are 100% correct or not.
So my so I I what I can do is I can
acknowledge the fact that there are
these claims that that that are made
repeatedly consistently about the
mountain which could perhaps indicate
there is some truth to it. Uh but what
could be the reason for this? I could
not possibly comment about that. Maybe
see illnesses are a bad thing. I don't
think people have illnesses there.
Certain illness that would be bad. The
mountain isn't an evil mountain. It's
it's one of the hol it's the holiest
mountain, right? It's the center of the
universe essentially. Mount Meu, Mount
Kilash. So illnesses are are are a
negative thing. I have not heard of
illnesses. I've heard of changes in the
perception of time and whatn not etc. I
can't say why that's the case.
Right angle says if we deploy the
strategy in Far East, we will launch
scheme in which we will give women
15,000 per month. This will stop convert
conversions.
Okay, we will give women women 15,000
per month. This will stop conversions.
The question is who will give this money
15,000 per month. Who?
Let's say there are 100,000 one lakh
women there. You give each woman each
woman
15,000 per month. What is 15,000 times 1
lakh?
15 lakhs 15,000 lakhs. 150 crores a
month you to spend. Who's going to spend
it? I don't have the means to spend 150
crores a month on a on a recurring
basis. Will the government do it? The
government doesn't give a damn about
Hinduism. Who will do it?
The government will not give any money
for stopping foreign conversions or or
or helping or aiding Hinduism. The
government will never do that.
So it's a it's a good strategy
conceptually.
But who will do it? Who will give the
money? That is the problem.
Cipher Ash says if India does make a
move on Pakistan and not just P but
liberating liberating Bjasthan maybe in
that case what happens to the land under
Chinese administration on Pakistan land
that are part part of Pakistan China
loan deal that remains under Chinese
occupation and because it is now
according to China Chinese territory you
have chi the Chinese army there nothing
happens to that land unless you go and
take it from the Chinese which will
launch a war between India and China.
So if you make a move on Pakistan Pok,
liberate Balojasthan, liberate P etc. it
will not change the status of the um
part of Kashmir that is under Chinese
occupation,
the Shakgam valley etc. It won't make
any uh change the status of that Chinese
occupied territory. So there is P, there
is also C. You're talking about C,
Chinese occupied Kashmir. That won't
change, right? Unless we go to war with
China.
Right angle says, "Can we pressure
Israel to stop funding of cookies? What
leverage do we have on Israel? How do
you see Israel from Bat's perspective
and Israel interested Bhat?
That is something for the government to
look into."
Yeah.
Yeah. So, what leverage do we have in
Israel? Nothing.
How do I see Israel from Bat's
perspective? Well, Israel is a valued
strategic partner. That's how I see it
from Bat's perspective. A valued
strategic partner.
What is Israel's interest with Bhat?
Well, we are valued strategic partners
of each other. We have a lot of uh um
shared interests, shared values. Um we
have economic interests. There are
that are mutually beneficial and so on
to this. We have strategic interests, we
have uh technological and military
interests and so on. So that's how I see
Israel from Bat's perspective.
Pratip Kumar Roy says about 2015 New
Year's Eve incident Germany.
Uh are they idiots?
No, they are barbarians.
You're talking about what happened in
Col, are you?
Um
Cologne New Year's Eve incident in
Germany.
Yeah, that
so that was
I doubt if anyone was punished for what
happened. That's Germany for you today.
Really? Now Miss Patel says yogis and
agoris see through deep meditation what
certain people on certain people on LSD
or DMT see for a few moments
consciousness levels that science can't
explain fascinating
yeah it is said that when you meditate
deeply when you are deep into meditation
there are levels of meditation the the
deeper you go inside into meditation
deeper inside yourself you you
experience things and apparently at a
certain stage of your meditation at a
certain depth
you experience and see things that
people typically see when they're on DMT
or LSD or whatever, right? Uh when
people are on DMT, they say they see
these these these u mechanical aliens or
space aliens or something. Apparently,
LSD has some I don't know fractal
patterns people see and whatnot. So when
you meditate, you do see things like
that if you meditate deep enough. And uh
yeah so the process of meditation seems
to uh affect the brain in a way that's
similar to what happens to the brain
brain under the effect of LSD or DMT or
whatever but in a purely natural manner
without actually ingesting chemicals. So
yes consciousness has levels that
science can't explain no question about
that indeed fascinating.
Pratep Kumar Roy says racism against
Indians was started by PewDiePie back in
2018. PewDiePie PewDiePie was one of the
contributors, one of the perhaps
principal
um
uh ring leaders possibly. Yeah, there
was this thing right PewDiePie versus
T-Series in which T-Series won and
PewDiePie had gone on this uh on this on
this campaign against T-Series by by
asking people to uh subscribe to him to
to showcase the superiority of Western
culture or to save Western culture,
civilization or something like that.
Okay, we're back. There was uh yeah, so
uh that was the deal.
And yeah, so PewDiePie was one of the
original instigators of anti anti-India
racism.
Pranjal Mishra says you once said that
you practice vipasha meditation. How was
your experience and do you still
practice it? I have practiced it in the
past. I am not a regular meditator any
anymore today. Uh vipasha is very
interesting and and yeah it's it's a
very good form of meditation.
It's about focusing on your breath.
Focusing on the if the the you close
your mouth and you breathe in and
breathe out naturally. Okay. When you
focus on how the breath feels on this
region and I can't give you tell you
more beyond that eventually you have to
shift the focus somewhere else and that
yeah so yeah vipasha can be done like 10
minutes a day 20 minutes a day depending
on can be done hours if you want um my
experience was very good I don't
practice it because yeah I should but I
don't but my experience was very good it
does have very profound positive effects
on you as a person. Yeah.
Gajjapati Dv says please start taking
UPI based questions. What's UPI? Unified
payment interface.
Um
I don't know how to take those. This uh
super chat thing is based on uh uh the
YouTube functionality. I suppose you can
do it by UPI also I suppose.
Or is UPI something else? I think it's
that right. So yeah, I I don't know how
to do it separately differently.
Hersh says your conclusion on Reanir's
latest podcast on Maratas and Rajuts if
you haven't seen it can give you a views
on next cast. I don't think I'll be
watching that. I don't watch podcast. I
don't have the time for that.
Let me let me quickly see what is this
podcast about. Um
give me a second.
Let's go. Uh, let me put that on the
screen.
Reanir's podcast. It must be on his uh
on his Hindi channel, right?
Real podcast. Um, what's the deal?
That's his thing.
Um,
history of Rajuts.
uh two days ago
there's a separate podcast on Maratai
Street. Yeah, listen I am not going to
have the time to watch this honestly to
be very honest with you to be very
frank. So I don't know I won't be able
to do it. Sorry.
Aravsha says I am a 14year-old kid. My
recent recently my paper titled
cosmology in the donder whale formalism
of Einstein carton gravity got published
in EPJC. Thank you for your guidance. Do
check it out. Oh, fantastic. Uh, let us
see. Let us, uh, try and look up the
paper, shall we?
Um, Aravsha.
Let's see.
Arav Sha, cosmology in the deep donder
wild formalism of Einstein carton
gravity.
Let's see. Okay, it's on the archive,
physics archive.
And you have this on the CERN
uh platform as well. It's there on
on uh inspire HP research gate.
Uh okay. Okay. Let's see the archive
version.
Ah Mr. Ulopov.
Very nice. Very nice. Very nice.
Fascinating. Fascinating. I will check
it out. Let me see the PDF.
Very nice.
Awesome. I will check out the full
paper. And uh until until then,
congratulations. That's fantastic.
You're 14 years old.
Outstanding. Outstanding. I could not be
happier. I could not be prouder of you.
Great job, sir. Great job, Ara. Keep
going.
Viri VHMA says every country has an army
but an army has a country that's
Pakistan. Every country has some
businessmen but some businessmen have
got a country that's the USA. Because of
them the world suffers what are my
thoughts? Well,
which country causes more suffering in
the world is the question you to ask
yourself. Does Pakistan cause more
suffering or does the US cause more
suffering?
In the case of Pakistan, the suffering
is
who suffers? It's the people of Pakistan
and the people of the neighboring
countries that suffer.
Um,
in the case of the superpower, the whole
world essentially suffers
in some way or the other, but the the
world also benefits from American
technology and what not. It depends on
how you see it, right? The technology
vasalizes you, but you also
benefit from it.
Um
so in the case of the US you are saying
that every country has some businessmen
but in the case of the US some
businessmen have the whole country which
is not entirely inaccurate which is not
far from the truth actually it's a small
bunch of businessmen who own the US
essentially. Yeah. Yeah.
Other says I saw an Indian vlogger show
the tomb of Kajay Rabi and tomb of
Piralandus.
They resemble a famous Indian monument
but monument but older than ours. What
do you think sir? How is it possible? I
have no idea man. What is Kaj Rabi? Um I
think you're going to talk about the Taj
Mahal I'm sure but let's see. Um
tomb of Kaj Rabi.
What is that?
Saf 17th century Safavidid Molium.
Okay. And what's the other one? Pier
Palandus.
What's Pirandus?
Okay. So, yeah. So, how old is this
thing? Per palandus. 1577 CE. Okay. What
do I think? It's all u what is
considered to be Islamic architecture,
right? It is what it is. Yeah.
Prod by Bisuj says should India put a
military base in Singapore? Look,
India should put a military base on the
moon and also on Mars.
But India can't, right? We all know why
India can't put a military base on the
moon and on Mars because we don't have
rockets that can reach there and so on
so forth all these logistical problems.
Would India have a put a base on
Singapore?
Is it feasible for India to do that? Is
it practical for India to do that? Will
Singapore allow it? Will the US allow
it? The answer is no. No, no, no, no.
I should have my own military, private
military base on Singapore,
right? I should have my own private
country also, right? Should I? But you
can dream of all these things, but you
can't do that, right? India can't have a
military base in Singapore.
Ideally, India should have a military
base in every country,
but we can't do it.
Okay, Gior TV says, "I meant a massive
parachute attached to the aircraft's
body, not the passengers that so that
that could deploy in emergencies to slow
the aircraft's descent and descent and
reduce impact in incidents like the
recent AirIndia crash. You would need an
enormous parachute. enormous parachute.
Okay, like
more than a square kilometer in size to
be able to sufficiently slow down an
aircraft's descent if it is falling, you
know, without power. You would need a
gigantic
parachute
and that will be very massive and and
and where do you store it? And that will
add so much weight to the aircraft.
So let's see. Okay, let's let's try and
say this. What's the weight of a typical
parachute? What is the weight of a
typical parachute that can handle a
human being?
Okay. 7 to 16 kg. Okay.
And specialized military systems. So
let's say it's 15 kg. And let's say the
average human being is 70 kg 1570.
What is the weight of a typical Boeing
airliner?
Okay. 79,000. So let's say a human being
is 79 kg. This is 79,000 kg. So you will
need a parachute. That's this is a very
rough and dirty calculation. a parachute
that will be about 20 tons in weight.
20 tons in weight. Enormous, gigantic.
It will be too costly in terms of, you
know, extra weight for the aircraft. It
will um and and secondly, where do you
store it? How do you deploy it in in
such a way that it will, you know, stop
the aircraft from from crashing? So
theoretically you can do it but uh
economically and practically highly
impractical. Yeah.
DD says critics say the UK education
softens the harms of the British Empire
in India. In a reverse timeline and
dominant Indian Empire might likewise
glorify gains and downplay atrocities.
Look,
every empire
which has done nasty stuff seeks to
whitewash its atrocities. No question
about that.
But a dominant Indian empire would never
do such atrocities unless you call the
Muggal Empire in Indian Empire which it
was not.
You've had Indian empires like the Chola
Empire which conquered and vasalized the
entirety of Southeast Asia. Do they did
they do any of the atrocities the
British did on India? The Cholas did
not. You had multiple Indian empires
that have conquered various parts of
Central Asia and so on. Did any Indian
Empire do any of those atrocities that
the British did on India? No.
So in a reverse timeline, a dominant
Indian empire would not do such
atrocities. It would not have to
downplay what it doesn't do. Right?
That's the point. That's the point.
Honey Sharma says, could you what could
you tell us about the Mayapur Delhi
radiation accident? How could 16 cobalt
60 pencils appear in a scrapyard? I
thought cobalt was safe. Cobalt. No,
there's a radioactive isotope of cobalt.
Okay. uh I am not aware of this of the
details of this Delhi Mayapur Delhi
radiation accident. What I can tell you
about is about cobalt. There's a
radioactive
isotope of cobalt. So
let's see the the the periodic table
periodic table.
Okay, we go to images. We uh search for
large images
and uh where is cobalt?
Where is cobalt?
Um, okay. Instead of doing that, let's
just search for
cobalt radioactive isotope.
Let's go. So, cobalt 60 is a radioactive
isotope of cobalt.
It's a synthetic radioactive isotope of
cobalt with a half life of 5 something
days. So yeah, that is used in various
applications and looks like that's what
was found in
possibly I haven't studied this incident
so I'm not aware of it. Sorry. Actually
Hanisha says I live in a small town so
so there's no self-defense academy here.
I asked about Krav Maga last week since
you said it I love to join an academy.
So what can I learn on YouTube which can
help me on a bad day? Um
I suppose there must be various videos
about street fighting, how to defend
yourself on in a street fight and so on.
You can use learn various techniques,
tactics, get a bunch of friends, two,
three friends and practice against each
other in a in a safe way, you know. So
you can learn from YouTube also, right?
Um various you could even learn basic
Krav maga from YouTube. But Krav Maga is
there are no rules in Krav Maga. It's
about using whatever you have access to
to neutralize your enemies in and
actually neutralize people. Okay. Ramaga
is all about eliminating opponents. Um
so I I I suppose you could learn certain
martial arts based on YouTube tutorials
and practice with your friends. You can
learn self-defense. You can learn how
to, you know, protect yourself in street
fights and so on. I suppose there must
be playlists and tutorials. So find
something that has high ratings and high
views and learn that practice that with
your friends. Yeah.
Her says, "Is it okay to be misogynistic
and toxic? Cause being good is not worth
in today's time. What are my views?" My
views is that it is never good to be
misogynistic or toxic even if the world
is evil. Even if the world is toxic and
misogynistic, why why do you have to be
like that?
Uh don't
don't let others change who you are.
That's my view. You be yourself. Most
likely you are not a toxic and
misogynistic person but you are feeling
frustrated and you feel like if everyone
is be being like this I should also do
that. Don't give into the temptation.
Don't let others don't let the
environment change who you are. Remain
true to yourself. That's my advice to
you sir. Ashre
Han Sharma says, "What makes Bumrah the
greatest? Is it just his bowling action
or the fact that he can extend his elbow
more than normally or is it is it just
sheer hard work?" So Bumrah is probably
one of the greatest of all time. If you
look at his uh if you look at his test
match record, his average even now must
be below 20, which is shocking. I mean
some of the all-time great like Glenn
McGra etc have average of 22 23. Bley
Ambrose average of 22 or 23 and Bumra is
below 20 strike rate very high. So he's
one of the all-time greats not the
greatest of all time as of now he still
has time but one of the unquestionable
all-time greats. So what makes him so so
tricky so difficult?
Definitely his action is very weird
isn't it? very strange action. He's
really stuttering runup and very strange
action. He's I suppose the ball
disappears for a while just like Jeff
Thompson used to do. I suppose if you're
the batsman, if you're facing Lumra,
maybe the ball disappears and then re
reappears. Um
his pace isn't exceptional. 140s. Yeah.
Which is definitely fast. He's a fast
bowler, not a medium pacer, but it's not
express. He's capable of express pace.
is capable of bowling in the 150s. I've
seen him do that, but he typically bows
in the in the low to mid 140s, sometimes
even even 130s. So, it's not the pace.
He does have a little bit of an hyper
extension of the elbow, right? See my
elbow, it's pretty much straight, but in
his case, it can hyper extend a bit. So
combination of these factors including
and the most
important factor probably his his is his
his extremely unorthodox bowling action.
So all of that that combination and his
fitness and everything and his
intelligence. He knows how to take
wickets. There are people I've seen
bowlers who can bowl fast but who don't
know how to take wickets.
You should you know taking wickets is an
art.
It's all about studying the opponent the
batsman. studying the body language,
what makes him comfortable, what makes
him uncomfortable and so on so forth. So
he should know how to take wickets and
Bumrah knows how to take wickets. So and
obviously he's very intelligent, he
studies, he's he works. So all these
factors together make him one of the
all-time greats.
I am too cool. Thank you very much, sir.
I am too cool. Thank you.
Uh Pratip Kumar Roy says, "What diet do
you follow?" Also, Professor Jang's
channel. I haven't still checked out
Professor Jang's channel. What diet do I
follow? I follow a regular diet. Nothing
exceptional about my diet. A regular
diet.
Diddi says, "Critics say UK education
softens." I I took this question a while
ago, just a couple of questions ago. So
yeah, I've already addressed this
question.
Hanish says from Joro, I work as a
system admin. My manager is a smoker.
Finally, I'm seeing people who smoke
with him are getting benefits. Oh, and I
faced some same issue in all my jobs
lately. How to deal with this?
So, Jo is is asking this question. I
work as a system admin. My manager is a
smoker. I am seeing people who smoke
with him are getting benefits. So, you
mean he's being partial towards his
fellow smokers and he's being biased
against you because you're non-smoker?
That's terrible.
And you faced the same issue in all my
jobs, all your jobs recently. How to
deal with this?
Find a job where nobody smokes.
Are all smokers like this? That they are
biased against non-smokers?
That's that's genuinely new for me. I
have never imagined that
really. Are smokers biased against
non-smokers?
I mean, I don't mean to make fun of the
situation, but that's incredible. I've
never this this is something genuinely
new for me. It's the first time I'm I'm
hearing this in my in my life.
I had no idea that smokers were like
that. So I would say if that's the case
that you have seen this in other jobs
too that smokers are biased against
non-smokers
then please find a job where nobody
smokes. That's the only solution I can
think of
and don't smoke. All right.
Sam the gamer says poll for no next
science episode
also can you explain the garbagginess of
the Indian education system in Hindi for
my father watching today. Look um
I would say
watch my the videos
I have you know
my previous Ask Kabit show episodes 28
what what were the episode numbers? Let
me once again do that. I can they be
played in in Hindi that would work in
that case. So go to my channel
uh go to oldest and uh yeah 28
30 and 31. These are the three episodes.
I am not sure if that can be viewed in
Hindi. If there is an option to do that,
I will enable it so that you can watch
in Hindi or at least watch with Hindi
sub subtitles and then hopefully that
will you know do the job that you seek.
So yeah,
please do that. I I I will see if if it
can be enabled which will help you out.
All right. Thank you.
Java bro says, did you see Dundar?
Can our spies not infiltrate CIA, Mosad,
etc. Can a patriotic Indian billionaire
infiltrate the deep state and share
insider info with our government? Look,
theoretically everything can be done.
I've seen Durand. Yes, I've seen it.
Good movie. Theoretically your spies can
infiltrate everything. But practically
will they practically
practically does the in government want
this to happen?
If it wants it to happen, does it give
everything the spies need to do these
things? So theoretically everything is
possible or spies can infiltrate CIA
Mossad
a patriotic Indian billionaire can
infiltrate the deep state and share info
with our government. But even if a
patriotic billionaire shares info with
our government, what will the government
of India do with it?
So theoretically everything is possible
practically a lot of things don't
happen.
Fraud Bisj says should Indian education
be more projectbased.
The Indian education system should be
based on achieving outcomes. What
outcomes do we want? We want people who
are highly skilled, highly competent as
early as possible in life. Not at the
age of 23, 24. Why not by the age of 16?
So if can if it can be achieved through
projects, sure we can have projects in
the Indian education system today. You
have projects in engineering and all but
you know the quality of those projects
and you know that these projects the
students take them outside and have
somebody else do the project for them
and then they bring it back and show it
and yeah you're approved. Everyone knows
what's happening and no one cares.
So making it simply project based will
not solve the problems. The whole system
has to be reformed. That's the deal.
Ab Shukla says do you know about Om
Valley of Bopal which is exactly Mshaped
one side of Bopal at center
thousand-year old Bjpur temple at other
end vinda ridge. I think extensive
archaeological study is required. Okay.
I am not aware of this. Om valley
exactly Mshaped
it's at one side of Bopal let's see
Bopal shall we let us see Bopal
let us go to the map we have hardly
opened the map today because I've not
got questions that needed that but let
us uh locate Bopal
uh where is it's in MP isn't it Bopal
Where is Bopal?
Give me a second. I need to locate Bopal
in MP.
Indor is a major city in MP.
The other is Bopal. Why am I not able to
locate Bopal? Okay.
Bopal, Madhya Pradesh.
Ah, okay. So let's look at the satellite
imagery. Where is this Om Valley? Do I
see something that shaped like Om?
Uh Om Valley Bopal. Let's see.
Om
Valley
Bopal. Where is that?
Okay. Om. Okay. I don't know. That's
something else.
So I'm not sure if I see something like
that from
from the satellite images, but I'm sure
there's something. So yeah, so thank you
for making me aware of this. I was not
aware of it. And uh if there is some
archaeological, you know, footprint or
some something there, then maybe we
should look into it. Yeah.
Danny says, "If I want to study medicine
abroad in this anti-immigration wave
going on,
which is friendly for Indians as
medicine is long learning curve,
I'm not aware. I have not studied or or
or researched which nations
offer good medical courses
and are also not anti-Indian
immigration. The USA is becoming more
and more anti-immigration for sure.
Canada, it's no longer a great place for
Indians to go to as students.
How is Australia's medical system? I'm
not sure. I mean, medical education
system, I'm not sure. So, I don't know.
I'm not the guy to ask this question. Uh
I'm not the guy who can answer this
question reliably. I don't know which
country offers you high quality med
medical education and is not anti-Indian
immigration. I don't know. You'll have
to do this research. Don't know. Sorry.
Honey Sharma says, "Is is it too early
to ask you?" I've not watched it, sir.
I've not watched Tumb. Please ask me
next week. I've not watched it yet.
Watched it yet. Sorry. Uh Right Angle
says, "If we choose to build 1,000
nuclear reactors,
US will try to stop or way may invade
India to stop India's energy
independence." Your view? Thanks.
There's no country that look how many
nuclear reactors does the does the US
have? I'm not sure if if they have even
a hundred. Let's see.
How many nuclear reactors does the
United States have?
It won't give me the answer. The AI
won't give the answer. How about that?
Okay. The US has had 93 operational
reactors.
Okay. As of 2023. So, forget about a
thousand.
Even a 100 is a big deal.
And if we are if we choose to build
let's say 100 reactors the nobody will
try to invade us. Uh they may try to
perhaps find some ways of slowing things
down and all but they won't invade India
for that. Hers says which states TFR
will go down in the future like Bihar
will be last I don't know sir I don't
know Bihar will be last. Why why do you
think that? I think the most
industrialized and developed states will
have TFRs going down first possibly but
which ones I am not sure.
Pratep Kumar Royce is about the smoker
thing. The fellow smokers generally are
snitches and they do butter the manager
for promotions. This is real stupid
politics everywhere. Yeah, that's
unfortunate.
Fellow smokers are snitches.
Well, that's smoker politics. I had no
idea that such things even existed.
Anyway, where you have human beings, you
have politics. That's the general rule.
Pratip Kumar Royce is your views about
Langotia University. Very, very
shameful, very terrible what happened.
Um, very embarrassing and it's simply a
system. It's simply a symptom
that shows that that tells you that the
disease that the Indian educ education
system has. It's rotten to the core.
It's corrupt. It's simply a system of
the actual underlying disease.
Kunal says is jantaar mantra
observations really copied from ulugabig
observatory historical sources and
historians say it was hugely inspired by
from those big observabs.
Janta mantra is in Delhi isn't it? It's
a place where people protest these days.
Um I am not aware of the history of the
jantaar mantra. It seems to be some kind
of observatory. I have no idea of Ulbig
Observatory.
Astronomy came from India. Ulbig was a
Turk. The Turks, what understanding
would they have of astronomy? What his
historical
tradition did they have of astronomy?
So, um I think if some historical
sources or historians make this claim,
maybe they're highly motivated.
Abir Shukla says if you will search Om
Valley Bopal on web let's do that
Om Valley Bopal
it's not Omali it's Om Valley
okay what is this Omali
images
okay this looks like an
Okay.
Interesting. So, it's a geographical
formation that looks like an M.
Got it. Okay.
Right angle says, "In my previous
question, I meant
government will fund like CM Bena
scheme. If you were PM, what would you
have done to stop conversion?"
YouTube will not allow certain words.
Okay. The government will use largely ba
scheme thing schemes like that to to uh
garner votes because these are
inducements. You are paying people money
using taxpayer money
because you're paying girls using
taxpayer money because they're girls.
That way hopefully you'll get some more
votes, right? So that's why the
government does that. Now will the
government use public funds to stop
conversions? They don't give a damn.
They don't give a damn. If I were the
PM, what would I have done to stop
conversions? Well, that is classified.
I can't say it here. And I'm not PM, so
it doesn't matter anyway. So,
okay. D said, I just came back from
Cambodia. I found it to be much cleaner
than India despite having a lower GDP
per capita. It's frustrating to see the
lack of civic sense. Yet, it will take
100 years to fix this. The root cause of
the problem in India
is not a lack of civic sense. It's
corruption. Allegedly, that is the
problem.
It's not civic sense. Civic sense isn't
there because there is no penalty for
littering and doing all that. The moment
there's a penalty, everybody would be
behave will be well behaved. The problem
is alleged corruption.
Gajjapati Dv says I meant amnant
amount is sent through UPI note part can
be used for question no changes by em
but you need to turn on your UPI app
notification on phone please consider it
I meant amount is sent through UPI note
part can be used for a question
no charges by
P.M.
You need to turn on your UPI app
notification on phone.
Oh, when you send a UPI payment on the
phone, you can send a note on the phone
on on the the but how do I display it
here?
I mean I suppose it's theoretically
possible but uh
but then the viewers won't be able to
see in real time the questions right
like what we can do here right now so it
it won't be very convenient for the
viewers for the audience right that's
the issue that's the issue I I really
appreciate you giving this option and
this recommendation but it's not very
convenient for the viewers they won't be
I have to read out the question and read
out who it is that asked the question
but you won't be able to see a So that
will be less convenient for the viewers.
That's the issue.
Adjit Singh says 1940s
Japan so smart that didn't need to amend
constitution for next 80 years. I know
what you mean. Yeah.
Prod says should India use Singapore
Singapore method for civic sense. Oh I
absolutely agree with it. I absolutely
am in favor of that. Use the Singapore
method for civic sense. Absolutely.
Discipline. hard discipline.
Okay, that I think that brings me to the
end of today's live stream. Almost 4
hours. Would you believe it? Almost 4
hours. All right. All right. Let's let's
now end this live stream. Thank you very
much. It's been almost 4 hours. Thank
you so much for your viewership, for the
questions, and I look forward to seeing
you in the next one which will be very
soon. Until then, take care. Keep asking
questions. Keep raising your standards.
See you in the next one. Take care.
Bye-bye.